[
    {
        "question_maker": "plight_worry",
        "question": "*internal screaming*",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "*external screaming*"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "prophet_hmm",
        "question": "I am not programmed to feel",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "It won't turn on."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "prophet",
        "question": "[That Lightbulb...! You Are Here!]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "M- me?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "prophet",
        "question": "[I Am Most Humbled By Your Presence. Yes!]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Uh, thanks..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "prophet",
        "question": "[May I First Ask How You Arrived Here?]",
        "response_character": "niko3",
        "response": "I'm... not sure..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "prophet_omg",
        "question": "[Oh!][So You Woke Up In An Unfamiliar, Dark Location?]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Mhm!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "prophet",
        "question": "[You Will Be The One To Save Our World From Eternal Darkness.]",
        "response_character": "niko2",
        "response": "...um."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "prophet",
        "question": "[Please Ask Me Anything!]",
        "response_character": "Niko",
        "response": "Ah, well...."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "prophet",
        "question": "[Always Look To Them For Guidance.][You've Already Received More Than You Realize...]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "When I woke up in that house...For some reason, I called out a name."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "prophet_omg",
        "question": "[Ah, That Would Be Our God!]",
        "response_character": "niko_pancakes",
        "response": "Oh! Right!I... think I..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "prophet",
        "question": "[So... How Did You Know?]",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "... ..hm..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "prophet_omg",
        "question": "[Have You Already ContactedPlayer, Then?]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Nope!I just have to close my eyes and focus, right?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "prophet",
        "question": "[Always Look To Them For Guidance.][You've Already Received More Than You Realize...]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "In the house, I found this... computer."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "prophet",
        "question": "[If I Had To Guess, They Might Be Trying To Pass The Message ToPlayer.]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "...Player?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "prophet",
        "question": "[In Fact, They Already Have.]",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Really?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "prophet",
        "question": "[Have You... Not ContactedPlayerYet?]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "I don't think so."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "prophet",
        "question": "[Please Close Your Eyes And Focus.]",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "Alright..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "prophet",
        "question": "[Updating Database...]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Hm?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "prophet",
        "question": "[Update Complete.]",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "I actually heard someone!They told me their name is actuallyPlayer!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "prophet",
        "question": "[Updating Database...]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Hm?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "prophet",
        "question": "[Update Complete.]",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "I actually heard someone!They told me their name is actuallyPlayer!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "prophet",
        "question": "[Updating Database...]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Hm?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "prophet",
        "question": "[Update Complete.]",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "I actually heard someone!They said their name isPlayer..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "prophet",
        "question": "[Why?]",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "It's a bad word!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "prophet",
        "question": "[Bad... Word?]",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "Nevermind."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "prophet",
        "question": "[Updating Database...]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Hm?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "prophet",
        "question": "[Update Complete.]",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "I actually heard someone!They said their name isPlayer..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "prophet",
        "question": "[Surely You Have More Questions!]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "I think that's all I have to ask for now."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "prophet",
        "question": "[Hello Again.]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Hi!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "prophet_omg",
        "question": "[Oh!]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Thanks for helping me and answering my questions!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "prophet_omg",
        "question": "[That Means I have Fulfilled My Purpose!]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Mhm!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "prophet",
        "question": "[Are There More Questions You Wish To Ask?]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": ""
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "prophet",
        "question": "[Go On Then, Ask Away.]",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Can you tell me about..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "prophet",
        "question": "[That's Why It's Called The Barrens.]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "...are there... ANY people living in this area?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "prophet",
        "question": "[I Was Not Built To Wander.]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "...not...built to?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "prophet",
        "question": "[I Cannot Desire Companionship.][I Have Not Been Tamed.]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Not... tamed?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "prophet",
        "question": "[There Was No Time.]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "I see..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "prophet",
        "question": "[The Savior Will Wake Up In A Strange House, Find The Sun, And Illuminate The World.]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Oh..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "prophet",
        "question": "[What Do You Mean?]",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "What else did you see in the prophecy?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "prophet",
        "question": "[???]",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Wait...  You ARE the prophet, right?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "prophet",
        "question": "[Good Heavens, No!]",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "But you called it \"my prophecy\" earlier..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "prophet",
        "question": "[That Just Means It Is Built Into My Programming.]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "...Your... what?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "prophet_hmm",
        "question": "[I Am A Robot, After All.]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "I see..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "prophet",
        "question": "[I Am Not Allowed To Answer.]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "But...how do I get up there?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "prophet",
        "question": "[In Time,PlayerWill Know What To Do.]",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "I...see."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver",
        "question": "[You can take it if you want. It may help you.]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Oh! Are you sure?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver",
        "question": "[Yes. I have many.]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Thank you!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver",
        "question": "[Please do not touch that.]",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Oh!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver_eyeclosed",
        "question": "[It could not even last a week without the sun.]",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "Sorry to hear that..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver_lookup",
        "question": "[All we can do is make use of the light we have.]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "This is some kind of power cell, apparently!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver_eyeclosed",
        "question": "[That's not important.]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Okay..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver_eyeclosed",
        "question": "[I told you not to touch it...]",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "Playermade me."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver",
        "question": "[I haven't played chess with anyone else for a very long time.]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Oh?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver_eyeclosed",
        "question": "[Nobody here is tamed, for that matter.]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "A bed."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver_eyeclosed",
        "question": "[These jars don't last very long.]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "A jar full of glowing shrimp."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver",
        "question": "[Doesn't look like it's glowing anymore, though.]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Do you know what I'm supposed to do with it?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver",
        "question": "[It will be important.]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "O...kay..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver_eyeclosed",
        "question": "[I'm sorry, I... don't even recognize this writing system.]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Ah, well, it was worth a shot."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver",
        "question": "[It will be important.]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "O...kay..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver",
        "question": "[There's no reason for you to linger in the Barrens.]",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Excuse me again, miss..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver",
        "question": "[Alright.What is the issue?]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "It said something about its navigation circuits being fried."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver2",
        "question": "[Just the navigation circuits?]",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Apparently!Playerand I fixed everything else, I think..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver",
        "question": "[If you let the rowbot borrow this, then its backup tracking system should activate.]",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "That's a very pretty necklace!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver_lookup",
        "question": "[Amber found from the Glen.]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "What's the thing inside the amber?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver",
        "question": "[...]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver_eyeclosed",
        "question": "[My programming says yes, but I still feel conflicted.]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "...?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver",
        "question": "[Here.]",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Oh, thank you!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver",
        "question": "[Do you need further assistance?]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "We're good, thanks!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver",
        "question": "[At least, nobody history knows.]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Then... who built it?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver_eyeclosed",
        "question": "[...]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Oh?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver2",
        "question": "[So, are you the \"messiah\"?]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "That's what I've been told."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver",
        "question": "[That's what you are, right? Some sort of cat?]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Nuh-uh!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver",
        "question": "[You got the eyes of a cat...]",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "But cats walk on four legs!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver_lookup",
        "question": "[A child like you being the messiah...just doesn't feel right.]",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "But that robot back there says there's no mistake..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver",
        "question": "[You've already seen how bad it can get, right?]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "We...haven't seen much of anything, actually..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver",
        "question": "[Then you must be headed towards the Tower.]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "M-hm!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver",
        "question": "[Maybe it will send you back home after you complete your mission.]",
        "response_character": "niko_pancakes",
        "response": "Oh!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver_eyeclosed",
        "question": "[Don't take my word for it, though.]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Before I go... Is there anything I can do in return?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver2",
        "question": "[Do you...  know how to play chess?]",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Yeah!Well, sort of..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver",
        "question": "[Then, will you play a game with me?]",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "I mean, I don't know the rules very well...."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver",
        "question": "[Thank you.It was built into my code.]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Ah."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver_eyeclosed",
        "question": "[Most of the robots here are not tamed.]",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Tamed?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver",
        "question": "[Watch out.]",
        "response_character": "niko_what",
        "response": "...there goes my bishop..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver",
        "question": "[Taming...  is complicated.]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Oh?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver",
        "question": "[...]",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "...there goes my other bishop..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver_eyeclosed",
        "question": "[Exactly where, I don't know.]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Oh?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver",
        "question": "[...]",
        "response_character": "niko_what",
        "response": "...there goes my little horse..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver",
        "question": "[Knight.]",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "Right..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver",
        "question": "[The world may be a very different place now.]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Because the sun is gone?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver_eyeclosed",
        "question": "[The sun's sudden death was just the tipping point, and things went south really fast after that.]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Oh..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver",
        "question": "[Check.]",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "W-what!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver_eyeclosed",
        "question": "[There's no guarantee that things will work out.]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "But..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver",
        "question": "[Checkmate.]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver",
        "question": "[I hope you get home safely.]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Ah, thank you also!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver",
        "question": "[If you must enter it, it is my duty to accompany you at least once.]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Oh, thanks!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver",
        "question": "[Ready to leave?]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Mhm."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver",
        "question": "[You were starting to black out...]",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "I...I saw something?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver2",
        "question": "[?]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "It was like a really short dream, just now."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver2",
        "question": "[Oh?]",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "I saw something like...A robot, with a yellow eye..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver2",
        "question": "[Are you sure you're okay?]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "...yeah."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver_eyeclosed",
        "question": "[I hope he's okay.]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "He doesn't look broken or anything..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver_eyeclosed",
        "question": "[Or... hallucination.][Whatever it is that living beings have.]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Hm..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver",
        "question": "[I never met him myself. Only heard of him from a friend of mine.]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Your friend, huh..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver",
        "question": "[Where did you... get that book?]",
        "response_character": "niko2",
        "response": "Oh, uh..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver",
        "question": "[But I... know who wrote the book.]",
        "response_character": "niko2",
        "response": "Oh?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver2",
        "question": "[...Really has me intrigued.]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Yellow... phosphor?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver",
        "question": "[My friend gave me this a long time ago.]",
        "response_character": "niko_pancakes",
        "response": "Pretty!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver2",
        "question": "[Well... it IS the same person.]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Oooh."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver2",
        "question": "[You said it JUST started glowing?]",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Yeah?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver2",
        "question": "[Maybe you should at least try to read it again...]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "I can see a faint yellow glow in the distance..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver",
        "question": "[Don't stand so close to the edge.]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Oh! Sorry!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver",
        "question": "[Without a vehicle, we can't proceed.]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Can't we walk?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver",
        "question": "[But for you it's a safety violation. I won't allow it.]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "What's ahead, anyway?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver",
        "question": "[This is what propelled the world into the industrial age.]",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "So now it's lost forever?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver",
        "question": "[Even the robots have been all cleared out and repurposed.]",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "That makes sense..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver",
        "question": "[Though there was one that always insisted on going back...]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Oh?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver",
        "question": "[I hope he's okay...]",
        "response_character": "niko2",
        "response": "...what... just happened?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver",
        "question": "[I'm not sure... I wasn't looking.]",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "To be honest... neither was I..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver",
        "question": "[Hmm...]",
        "response_character": "niko2",
        "response": "...what... just happened?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver",
        "question": "[...which means it likely detected the motion in this room and sent itself over.]",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "Ah... that does make sense."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver",
        "question": "[If you wanted to, we now have that option.]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver_lookup",
        "question": "[No.]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "But I wanted you to come with us..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver",
        "question": "[I would just have to follow along on the rails.]",
        "response_character": "niko_what",
        "response": "But doesn't it look a little...  precarious...?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver",
        "question": "[Which you are.]",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "Gotcha."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver_eyeclosed",
        "question": "[Probably even part of a robot, at one point.]",
        "response_character": "niko_what",
        "response": "Oh..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver_eyeclosed",
        "question": "[...or not. I don't know.]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Okay, here we go."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver",
        "question": "[What's wrong?Do you want to head back?]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "I have a weird feeling about this..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver",
        "question": "[Sounds good.]",
        "response_character": "niko_distressed",
        "response": "Oh..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver",
        "question": "[Hm...? What's wrong?]",
        "response_character": "niko_distressed",
        "response": "I..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver",
        "question": "[Do you want to head back, then?]",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "I... don't know..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver",
        "question": "[Alright.]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Some sort of computer."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver3",
        "question": "[Earthquake...]",
        "response_character": "niko_surprised",
        "response": "Th-the tunnel back out just collapsed!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver_worry",
        "question": "[No!!]",
        "response_character": "niko3",
        "response": "What are we gonna do?!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "proto1",
        "question": "[Both of you. Follow me.]",
        "response_character": "niko3",
        "response": "Where to?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "proto1",
        "question": "[The way out.]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Some sort of small machine."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver",
        "question": "[Let's go.]",
        "response_character": "niko2",
        "response": "Oh, the cart's stopped!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver2",
        "question": "[What...?]",
        "response_character": "niko2",
        "response": "Huh?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver",
        "question": "[But the power was cut off so long ago...]",
        "response_character": "niko6",
        "response": "Weird!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver2",
        "question": "[Whatever it is, I need to investigate.]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Okay..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver2",
        "question": "[Will you be okay by yourself for a bit?]",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Don't worry!Player's with me!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver_eyeclosed",
        "question": "[Alright. Stay safe.]",
        "response_character": "niko4",
        "response": "I shouldn't get too close..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver_eyeclosed",
        "question": "[Still at it.]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "How's it going?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver_eyeclosed",
        "question": "[This is really bothering me...]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "How's it going?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver2",
        "question": "[I've actually never been into this particular one.]",
        "response_character": "niko2",
        "response": "Really?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver_eyeclosed",
        "question": "[They all look the same.]",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "Fair enough!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver_eyeclosed",
        "question": "[But... I have never seen any cameras around.]",
        "response_character": "niko_what",
        "response": "That's kind of spooky!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver2",
        "question": "[You were in there for a while.]",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Yeah! We... ..found...a"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver",
        "question": "[Come on, let's go back.]",
        "response_character": "niko3",
        "response": "I shouldn't get too close..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "proto1b",
        "question": "[....Niko?]",
        "response_character": "niko3",
        "response": "Y...yes?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "proto1b",
        "question": "[....What is your name?]",
        "response_character": "niko2",
        "response": "I'm Niko..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "proto2",
        "question": "[Do you know who sent you?]",
        "response_character": "niko2",
        "response": "Oh.......um..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "proto2",
        "question": "[...]",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "The robot looks a little bit like you, even!Maybe you... know each other?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "proto1",
        "question": "[I cannot say.]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Oh?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "proto1",
        "question": "[A lot of my memories have been removed for safety reasons.]",
        "response_character": "niko_wtf",
        "response": "Your memories were removed?!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "proto1b",
        "question": "[How did you get here, then?][How did you reach this room?]",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Oh!We got here in a minecart!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "proto1",
        "question": "[But the minecart wasn't there when you entered the mines, was it?]",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "Oh yeah..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "proto1b",
        "question": "[So... how did you find it?]",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "I didn't really find it..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "proto1b",
        "question": "[Interesting. Please show me this journal.]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Okay..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "proto_disk",
        "question": "[...]",
        "response_character": "niko_what",
        "response": "Um..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "proto1",
        "question": "[Here.]",
        "response_character": "niko2",
        "response": "What... IS that?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "proto2",
        "question": "[Now, you will need to find a way to install the backup.]",
        "response_character": "niko2",
        "response": "Install the..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "proto1c",
        "question": "[Someone aside fromPlayer.][A resident of this world.]",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Yeah! The robot lady with the red hair."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "proto2b",
        "question": "[I can't be seen like this.]",
        "response_character": "niko2",
        "response": "Um... okay..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "proto2",
        "question": "[Please help me restore my memory.][Bring the disk back once you have the backup.]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Does this work?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "proto_gasp2",
        "question": "[...][Ah.]",
        "response_character": "niko2",
        "response": "Are you okay?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "proto2",
        "question": "[...Sure.]",
        "response_character": "niko2",
        "response": "So... I guess it worked?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "proto2",
        "question": "[I was built to greet the savior of the old world.]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "...wait.A prophet robot... like that one I met?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "proto2",
        "question": "[That is to say, he is much more primitive by comparison.][Embarassingly so.]",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "Hey, he seemed alright to me..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "proto1b",
        "question": "[I was built before the real world ended.]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "The.....real world?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "proto1b",
        "question": "[Niko...][Do you... remember the ending?]",
        "response_character": "niko3",
        "response": "...excuse me?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "proto1",
        "question": "[The fact that you've found me at all... means this is not your first time in this world.]",
        "response_character": "niko2",
        "response": "..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "proto_eyeclosed",
        "question": "[What matters is that you are here now.]",
        "response_character": "niko3",
        "response": "..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "proto2b",
        "question": "[Playerhas successfully bypassed the \"one shot\" restriction and brought you back again.]",
        "response_character": "niko2",
        "response": "I... .."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "proto2",
        "question": "[...Hm?]",
        "response_character": "niko_distressed2",
        "response": "...I...THOUGHT something was weird...."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "proto2b",
        "question": "[...to some extent.]",
        "response_character": "niko_distressed_talk",
        "response": "It's... just this weird feeling, okay?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "proto2b",
        "question": "[Look, just like how my memories were locked away, yours are too.]",
        "response_character": "niko_distressed2",
        "response": "...but."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "proto1",
        "question": "[Just... close your eyes and focus.]",
        "response_character": "niko3",
        "response": "...focus on what?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "proto2b",
        "question": "[No matter what you saw in the Tower, the top room never changes.]",
        "response_character": "niko2",
        "response": "...Alright."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "proto2",
        "question": "[There we go.]",
        "response_character": "niko_distressed2",
        "response": "I... can't remember all that much, but..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "proto1",
        "question": "[NPC memories do not last beyond the scope of a session.]",
        "response_character": "niko2",
        "response": "N...PC?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "proto2B",
        "question": "[Doesn't really exist unlessPlayerinitiates the program.]",
        "response_character": "niko_shock",
        "response": "..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "proto2",
        "question": "[We are all in it right now.]",
        "response_character": "niko_shock",
        "response": "....."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "proto2b",
        "question": "[IfPlayerends the program, the world will go into a stasis.]",
        "response_character": "niko3",
        "response": "Does... doesPlayerknow this?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "proto2b",
        "question": "[...All of that is consistent with their concept of what a computer game looks like.]",
        "response_character": "niko_distressed",
        "response": "..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "proto2b",
        "question": "[...\"Fake\" is a harsh word, but...]",
        "response_character": "niko_distressed2",
        "response": "And...why...didPlayernever tell me anything about... any of this..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "proto2b",
        "question": "[...I cannot speak forPlayer.]",
        "response_character": "niko_distressed2",
        "response": "I... just want to go home..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "proto2b",
        "question": "[Correct.]",
        "response_character": "niko_distressed",
        "response": "Is this why... I feel like..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "proto2b",
        "question": "[...but at this point, the world can never be truly saved.]",
        "response_character": "niko_distressed2",
        "response": "That's..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "proto_gasp2",
        "question": "[Wait, what?]",
        "response_character": "niko_upset_meow",
        "response": "Why would you make a world that's doomed from the beginning?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "proto2",
        "question": "[Playerdid not build the world, Niko.]",
        "response_character": "niko3",
        "response": "Oh..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "proto2b",
        "question": "[Even if you bring back the sun, it will not go away.]",
        "response_character": "niko3",
        "response": "The square stuff, isn't it?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "proto1b",
        "question": "[You managed to find me, after all.]",
        "response_character": "niko2",
        "response": "...?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "proto2",
        "question": "[You being here was due to his help.]",
        "response_character": "niko2",
        "response": "Oh...I guess it has something to do with the journal?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "proto2",
        "question": "[Whatever you did in your last session, you should stick with it for now.]",
        "response_character": "niko4",
        "response": "I..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "proto2",
        "question": "[Alright, then go do that.]",
        "response_character": "niko3",
        "response": "But..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "proto2",
        "question": "[There are plenty of machine parts around the Barrens that can be repurposed.]",
        "response_character": "niko_upset",
        "response": "............"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "proto2b",
        "question": "[...that was sarcasm.]",
        "response_character": "niko_upset",
        "response": "Knowing everything isn't real..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "proto1b",
        "question": "[But you DO want to go home, right?]",
        "response_character": "niko3",
        "response": "Yeah, but..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "proto2b",
        "question": "[Because this session might be the last one.]",
        "response_character": "niko3",
        "response": "...?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "proto2b",
        "question": "[There might not be enough internal resources left forPlayerto be able to generate another session after this.]",
        "response_character": "niko3",
        "response": "..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "proto1b",
        "question": "[But please, be careful.]",
        "response_character": "niko3",
        "response": "What about you?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "proto2b",
        "question": "[...Need to take care of something first.]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Does this work?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "proto2",
        "question": "[...This disk is blank.]",
        "response_character": "niko_83c",
        "response": "Whoops!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "proto2b",
        "question": "[...But you kinda started freaking out.]",
        "response_character": "niko_upset2",
        "response": "Sorry..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "proto2b",
        "question": "[...might explain why your memories felt like they were from a long time ago.]",
        "response_character": "niko_upset2",
        "response": "..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "proto2b",
        "question": "[Trying to establish a connection here...]",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "Sorry..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver_eyeclosed",
        "question": "[Understood.]",
        "response_character": "niko2",
        "response": "O...okay..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver2",
        "question": "[Come on, I'll wait for you outside.]",
        "response_character": "niko3",
        "response": "Wait! I want to ask you-"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "proto2b",
        "question": "[Causing mass confusion in the world's residents would likely result in unfavorable conditions for you.]",
        "response_character": "niko4",
        "response": "Alright..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "proto2b",
        "question": "[...We never had this conversation, remember?]",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "Sigh."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "proto2b",
        "question": "[I am not strong.]",
        "response_character": "niko2",
        "response": "I'm not that strong either..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver_eyeclosed",
        "question": "[...must be hidden.]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "I don't think we need to use this anymore,Player."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver",
        "question": "[Let's go.]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "So this is the way out?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "proto1",
        "question": "[Niko, get in the minecart.]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "O-Okay."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver3",
        "question": "[Watch out!]",
        "response_character": "niko_distressed",
        "response": "We can't go back..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver_rip",
        "question": "[...ughh]",
        "response_character": "niko_surprised",
        "response": "ARE YOU OKAY?!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "proto2b",
        "question": "[Come on.]",
        "response_character": "niko3",
        "response": "But what about her?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "proto_eyeclosed",
        "question": "[Come on.]",
        "response_character": "niko_upset",
        "response": "Player..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "proto1",
        "question": "[Hi.]",
        "response_character": "niko_distressed2",
        "response": "..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "proto2b",
        "question": "[...]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "And that robot was saying something."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "proto_gasp2",
        "question": "[...No!!.]",
        "response_character": "niko_shock",
        "response": "What do we do!!!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "proto2",
        "question": "[You have to take this.]",
        "response_character": "niko3",
        "response": "Wh- what?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "proto1C",
        "question": "[When you're in the city, go find someone named Cedric. Give him the disk.]",
        "response_character": "niko3",
        "response": "But... what happens if I..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "blue_gatekeeper",
        "question": "[What Are You Doing Here?]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Hm?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "blue_gatekeeper",
        "question": "[A Living Person Such As Yourself Should Have Evacuated This Place Long Ago.]",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Oh, but I just got here!To this world, I mean!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "blue_gatekeeper",
        "question": "[Have You Spoken To Prophetbot?]",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "I think so, yeah!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "blue_gatekeeper",
        "question": "[Prophetbot Was Built With The Sole Purpose Of Greeting You.]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Really?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "blue_gatekeeper",
        "question": "[Yes. He Cannot Speak With Anyone Else.][At Least, Not With Ease.]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Oh...that's...kind of sad..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "blue_gatekeeper",
        "question": "[Even Though The Residents Have Long Gone, I Must Remain.]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Ah..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "blue_gatekeeper",
        "question": "[I Have Not Been Tamed.]",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Tamed?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "blue_gatekeeper",
        "question": "[It Was Not Worth The Effort.]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "rowbot",
        "question": "[YOU'LL NEED TO LEAVE BEHIND SOME OF YOUR POSSESSIONS.]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Oh.Well... I don't think I'll be needing this crowbar anymore...Or this gas mask and gloves..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "rowbot",
        "question": "[THAT IS ACCEPTABLE.ONWARDS WE GO.]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "um....Player?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "rowbot",
        "question": "[I  WOULD HAVE GIVEN YOU THE COORDINATES, BUT...]",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "I need something I can use to wash the robot with!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "rowbot",
        "question": "[I HAVE NO OTHER CHOICE.]",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "There!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "rowbot",
        "question": "[WHERE WOULD YOU LIKE TO GO?]",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Can you take me to the Tower?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "rowbot",
        "question": "[MY BUILT-IN NAVIGATION CIRCUITS HAVE FRIED.]",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "I'm....  gonna assume that's not good."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "rowbot",
        "question": "[ONCE AGAIN I CANNOT FOLLOW MY PROGRAMMING.]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Aw..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "rowbot",
        "question": "[SHE WILL KNOW WHAT TO DO.]",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Wait! I need to protect my hands!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "rowbot",
        "question": "[WAS IT YOU WHO FIXED THE GENERATOR?]",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Well,Playerhelped me!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "rowbot",
        "question": "[...]",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Are you... okay?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "rowbot",
        "question": "[I CANNOT MOVE.]",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "Well, you're still really rusty..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "rowbot",
        "question": "[THAT IS TRUE.]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Hold on...Playerand I will find a way to help you!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "rowbot_off",
        "question": "...",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "rowbot",
        "question": "[`P%#LE  ASE D0 N0T AP PRO%4AC H]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Oh no!Is there anything I can do to help?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "rowbot",
        "question": "[LEAVE  `T#HIS AR`E A.]",
        "response_character": "niko3",
        "response": "..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "rowbot",
        "question": "[HERE IS YOUR STOP. THE GLEN.]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Thank you!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "rowbot",
        "question": "[THERE SHOULD BE A VILLAGE TO THE NORTH. BUT THAT'S ALL I CAN RECALL.]",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Oh, that's good to know!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "rowbot",
        "question": "[MAY YOUR MISSION BE A SUCCESS.]",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "A-Are you leaving?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "rowbot",
        "question": "[YES.I MUST RETURN TO MY STATION.]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "But you'll be all alone again..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "rowbot",
        "question": "[I HAVE NOT BEEN TAMED.]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "The horizon is glowing blue."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "alula",
        "question": "But I don't!",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Same!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "alula",
        "question": "But I don't!",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Same!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "shepherd",
        "question": "You've provided a great service for all of ramkind.In return...Take this fine ram wool.",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Oh, uh... thanks."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "shepherd",
        "question": "My rams clock at 1333 megaherds.",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "...what?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "shepherd",
        "question": "Good luck.",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Hello."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "shepherd",
        "question": "Hm...I need someone to help me herd my rams...",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Oh! I can do that!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "shepherd",
        "question": "Hmm...But you are carrying the sun.",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "Ah..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "shepherd",
        "question": "I cannot.I am but a simple shepherd.",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "Um... okay..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "shepherd",
        "question": "Would you like to help me herd my rams?There's a great reward in store for you, I promise.",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Uh..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "shepherd",
        "question": "Good luck.",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Looks like we gotta herd some rams now, Alula."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "alula",
        "question": "Can I help?",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Sure!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "alula_speak",
        "question": "Moss is tasty!",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Oh? What do they taste like?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "alula",
        "question": "Fish!",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Seriously?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "alula_pout",
        "question": "And wasteful!",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "This ram is chewing on a ball of moss."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "alula_speak",
        "question": "I like pickles!",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "I don't!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "alula",
        "question": "What's a fire?",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "We have much to discuss."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "alula_gasp",
        "question": "Gaaaaaaaasp!",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "There's peas in there!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "alula_speak",
        "question": "Why are you spinning around like that?",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "You're gonna get dizzy!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "alula_pout",
        "question": "I've only seen the sun when I was a little baby...",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Well, I'm here now..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "alula",
        "question": "What's a cat?",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "Something that I'm not!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "alula",
        "question": "?",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "It's an animal that walks on four legs and hunts mice and rats!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "alula_gasp",
        "question": "Like a fox?",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "I... guess?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "alula_speak",
        "question": "Foxes are cool!",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Looks like moss..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "alula_oh",
        "question": "Other... lady?",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Yeah! She's this robot and she seemed kinda sad..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "magpie_smile",
        "question": "I'm not sure what this is, actually!Some sort of fabric dye?",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Hmm... How about it,Player?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "magpie_smile",
        "question": "Pleasure doing business!",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Wait,Player... you want to...haggle?..really?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "magpie",
        "question": "Okay, okay...In that case, I'll also throw in this commemorative T-shirt!",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Uh..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "magpie",
        "question": "Oh well, then.Come back anytime.",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "Player, no..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "magpie_smile",
        "question": "What, you wanna trade it back?",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "Not really..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "magpie_hm",
        "question": "The shepherd was handing those out a while ago.But does it LOOK like it'll fit me?",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Huh?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "magpie_smile",
        "question": "T-Shirts aren't exactly made for people with wings!",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Wait, trade this?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "magpie_oh",
        "question": "I can't take this!",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "I'm not trading that,Player!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "magpie",
        "question": "What's that? A feather?",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Mhm!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "magpie_smile",
        "question": "Y'know, with you being the savior and all.",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Um... okay."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "magpie_oh",
        "question": "...hey!",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "I don't think it's right to trade this away,Player..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "magpie",
        "question": "I've dug up a couple of these before.",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Oh?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "magpie_smile",
        "question": "Yeah! There's this guy who would trade me the BEST things for them.",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Oh?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "magpie_hm",
        "question": "I don't know what it's called, but you have to wind it up...",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Music box?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "magpie_smile",
        "question": "I wanna do more trades with him!",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "How about this...glass tube full of water I got from a robot?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "magpie_smile",
        "question": "Do I!",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "...do you?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "magpie",
        "question": "That's why I set up a tradepost in the first place.",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "So I guess that's a no-go..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "magpie",
        "question": "Heya!You here to trade?",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Trade?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "magpie",
        "question": "Make me an offer and I'll give you something in return!",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Hm...Do we have something like that,Player?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "magpie_smile",
        "question": "It sure is!",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Shiny things are spread out on the rug."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "magpie",
        "question": "I just think they're neat!",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "The doorway is full of vines,Player..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "alula_oh",
        "question": "This is the shrine where the old prophet used to live...",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Oh?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "alula_speak",
        "question": "Back when she was still alive, I think?",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "It's a staff."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "maize_smile1",
        "question": "It's so warm...",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "That's... good, right?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "alula_oh",
        "question": ".....",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "...Alula? You okay?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "maize",
        "question": "I can't believe it...You're real...",
        "response_character": "niko_shock",
        "response": "....miss?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "maize",
        "question": "No....",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "W-we should get you to the village!Maybe they could-"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "maize",
        "question": "It's....okay...It's okay........too late for me.",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "But..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "maize",
        "question": "...Savior, if it's not too much trouble...Can you lend me the sun for a while?",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "I...Will it make you better?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "maize",
        "question": "I just want to experience the sun one more time before I... Well...",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "Oh..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "maize",
        "question": "Would it...Would it be too selfish of me to ask?",
        "response_character": "niko2",
        "response": "It's the sun."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "alula_pout",
        "question": "...ah.",
        "response_character": "niko_surprised",
        "response": "T-The light's gone out...!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "alula",
        "question": "I was trapped in there for so long...",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "So are you Alula?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "alula_speak",
        "question": "Wow! The messiah really does know everything!",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "Actually... I just met your brother earlier."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "alula",
        "question": "Can you bring me to him?",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Wait a minute...How did you know that I was the, um, messiah?I don't have the sun with me..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "alula",
        "question": "Your eyes!",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Huh?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "alula_speak",
        "question": "They reminded me of the sun!",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Oh!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "alula",
        "question": "That's why you're our messiah, right?",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Well... I...A lot of people back in my home world have eyes like mine..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "alula_pout",
        "question": "Home... world?",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Yeah! I'm actually from another world, you see!It's a place where the sun is in the sky and not in a Tower."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "alula",
        "question": "Do you like this world too?",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "I...Yeah."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "alula_speak",
        "question": "But that's ok! You're here now!You can make everything better!",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Yeah..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "alula_speak",
        "question": "Haha!",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Oh, shoot!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "alula",
        "question": "I'll be up ahead!",
        "response_character": "niko_what",
        "response": "..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "calamus_speak",
        "question": "Oh, by the way, what happened to the sun?",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "I lent it to someone in the ruins.She said she wanted to feel the sun again, before she..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "calamus_speak",
        "question": "Oh, you must be talking about Maize.",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Is that her name?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "calamus_sad",
        "question": "...but once the sun died, her health rapidly deteriorated.",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "Oh..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "calamus",
        "question": "I'm glad you were able to find her in time.",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "I think we might be already too late to save her..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "alula_speak",
        "question": "Here, we want you to have this!",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Oh, a feather!The edges are glowing yellow!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "calamus_speak",
        "question": "It's a sacred feather from the great Prophet.",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Oh?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "alula_gasp",
        "question": "Her feathers can glow in the dark and she can see into the future!",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "What!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "calamus",
        "question": "Father wanted to pass this down as an heirloom, although.....it feels more fitting for you to have it.",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "A-are you sure?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "calamus",
        "question": "I think that's what father would have wanted.",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Thank you!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "alula_speak",
        "question": "Wooow! That's a pretty necklace!",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "The robot lady from the Barrens gave it to me!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "alula_gasp",
        "question": "You've been to the Barrens?",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Yeah!Playerand I came from there, actually!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "alula_pout",
        "question": "But... I thought you came from another world...",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Ah, I just meant we were there first, before we got to the Glen!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "alula_speak",
        "question": "It's good to be home again!",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Fireflies!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "calamus_heh",
        "question": "I'll... deal with it later.",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "Looks like spoiled food."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "calamus_heh",
        "question": "I guess that's what happens if you leave your house for three days...",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Coals."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "calamus_heh",
        "question": "I really need to finish this...",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "There's a clover symbol on the cover of this book."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "calamus_shame",
        "question": "Gosh, I still need to finish studying it...",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Oh?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "calamus_smile",
        "question": "He's also the one who taught me how to read!",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Oooh!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "calamus_smile",
        "question": "I have a few more of his books somewhere...",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "It's a plush toy!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "alula",
        "question": "My fox is named Ruby, by the way!",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "It's a plush toy!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "alula_speak",
        "question": "That's mine! Our friend gave it to me last year!",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Oh?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "alula_gasp",
        "question": "Yeah! He has a fox too!And she can even talk!",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "...what?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "alula",
        "question": "So he got me a fox plush for Solstice Day!",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Oh! That's nice of him!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "alula_speak",
        "question": "He's the best!",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "It's a fishing pole."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "calamus",
        "question": "That reminds me, I need to go fishing later...",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "It's a fishing pole."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "alula",
        "question": "Do you like fish, Niko?",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Yeah!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "alula_speak",
        "question": "So do we! |They're good in stews.",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Or soups!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "alula_speak",
        "question": "Ewww!",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "Yeup."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "alula_oh",
        "question": "Niko? What's wrong?",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Huh?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "calamus_shock",
        "question": "You looked like you were about to faint!",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "It happened again..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "calamus_speak",
        "question": "A vision?",
        "response_character": "niko2",
        "response": "Vision?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "calamus",
        "question": "Like something a prophet would see.",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Whoa!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "calamus_speak",
        "question": "I mean, if you can talk toPlayer, it would make sense, right?",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "I... guess?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "calamus",
        "question": "...or not, I don't know.I've only read about it before.",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Oooh...Anyway, what is this place?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "calamus",
        "question": "We don't have a way getting there now, remember?There isn't a boat and none of us can swim, and...",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "What's...the sacred grounds?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "alula",
        "question": "Sometimes we go there to visit mom!Well, her grave, anyway.",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "Oh....-wait, how do you get there?I thought you said there isn't a boat?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "alula",
        "question": "I wonder when he'll come back?I wish we could go see mom again...",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "alula_speak",
        "question": "Okay!",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "It's a clover."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "calamus_unknown",
        "question": "Alula?Alula? Where did you go?",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Player, did you hear that?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "calamus_unknown",
        "question": "Alula!",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "I think it's coming from south-east of here."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "calamus",
        "question": "Are you our savior?",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "I... yeah?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "calamus_shame",
        "question": "Sorry for my rudeness!",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Huh? It's alright..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "calamus",
        "question": "I've been looking all over, but...",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "What does she look like?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "calamus_speak",
        "question": "Um... a little shorter than you, long blue hair, two blue feathers on top of her head...",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "I'm sorry, I haven't seen anyone like that..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "calamus_sad",
        "question": "Thank goodness...",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Are you from the village?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "calamus_sad",
        "question": "Still...If it gets any worse, we might have to find somewhere else to live...",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "What is this...square... stuff, exactly?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "calamus_speak",
        "question": "Obviously, you should avoid them too.",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "I will!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "calamus",
        "question": "I can't thank you enough for rescuing my sister, savior...",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Just call me Niko!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "calamus_shame",
        "question": "Oh gosh! Would it not be rude to call you by name?",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Huh?Why would it be?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "alula",
        "question": "Let's go!",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "I'm sorry, but I thinkPlayermight want to go somewhere else right now!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "calamus_speak",
        "question": "Oh, by the way, what happened to the sun?",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "I lent it to someone in the ruins.She said she wanted to feel the sun again, before..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "calamus",
        "question": "I guess they've all... gone.",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "I'm glad she got to see the sun again, at least."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "green_gatekeeper",
        "question": "[Good luck.]",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "Player, I'm too tired to go on right now...Please let me nap for a bit somewhere."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "green_gatekeeper",
        "question": "[Indeed You Do.][But Are You Not Forgetting Something?]",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "...Oh, the sun!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "green_gatekeeper",
        "question": "[I saw you carrying the sun earlier.You're the messiah, then?On your way to the Tower?]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Mhm."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "green_gatekeeper",
        "question": "[You can enter the Refuge through this wall.You'll need to sign your name in this scroll first.]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Alright....Do you have a pen?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "green_gatekeeper",
        "question": "[Perhaps you should look around the Glen for another.]",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "The doorway is full of vines,Player..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "red_gatekeeper",
        "question": "[Hello Again, Messiah, Do You Need Help?]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Well..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "red_gatekeeper",
        "question": "[Do You Understand What You Must Do Here?]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "I'm supposed to go inside the Tower, right?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "red_gatekeeper",
        "question": "[On The Surface.]",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "The surface?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "red_gatekeeper",
        "question": "[Look Down, Small One.]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Oooh, we're pretty high up!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "red_gatekeeper",
        "question": "[Finding The Entrance May Be Easy, But That Alone Will Not Be Enough.]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "What...do you mean?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "red_gatekeeper",
        "question": "[Once You Reach The Surface, I Recommend Visiting The Library For Leads.]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Alright..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "red_gatekeeper",
        "question": "[Only The Bearer Of The Sacred Kernel Is Permitted Access To The Garden.]",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Oh! Like... a kernel of corn...?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "red_gatekeeper",
        "question": "[Then, It Is Your Duty To Regrow Her.Do You Understand What You Must Do?]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Um..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "red_gatekeeper",
        "question": "[You May Now Pass Through Here To Access The Garden.]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Player? Are you there?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "plight",
        "question": "I'm too busy for this!",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "...Uh"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "plight",
        "question": "Is there, uh, anything I can help you with?",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Yes please!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "plight",
        "question": "....yeah, just take a look at it.",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "I-It looks like an elevator..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "plight_shock",
        "question": "Whoa! How did you make this?",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Out of a coffee can!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "plight",
        "question": "Guess I did it.",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "You sure did!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "plight_worry",
        "question": "Being so unproductive for so long... It's really getting to me...",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "I thinkPlayerand I got it handled!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "plight_worry",
        "question": "That... sure took you a while, huh...",
        "response_character": "niko2",
        "response": "Oh, shoot! You've been waiting this whole time?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "plight_worry",
        "question": "Well I uh... didn't want to be rude...",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "I'm sorry, I should've told you to go on ahead..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "plight_worry",
        "question": "M...maybe it exploded...",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Do you think we'll have to make a new one?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "plight_worry",
        "question": "How?",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "We'll figure it out!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "plight_why",
        "question": "...Don't ask me how magnets work, though. I didn't even finish high school...",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Alright, let's hope this works!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "plight_2b",
        "question": "Hey, you tried.",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Let's hope this works..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "plight_wtf",
        "question": "That's... never happened before.",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "The... squares?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "plight_worry",
        "question": "Huh?",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "You saw them, right?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "plight",
        "question": "But then again, the elevator hasn't been this broken before...",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Hmmm...."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "plight",
        "question": "You're a genius, you know that?",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Well, I had help fromPlayertoo!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "plight_unknown",
        "question": "Work already!!!",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Huh?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "plight_unknown",
        "question": "WHY. ISN'T. THIS. WORKING??!?",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "...I..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "plight",
        "question": ".......",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "......."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "plight",
        "question": ".............",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "............."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "plight",
        "question": "Sure is taking a while...",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "m-hm!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "plight_worry",
        "question": "(oh goodness gracious I'm stuck in an elevator with the messiah and also literally god themself this is awkward)",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Oh, maybe we can chat to pass the time, then?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "plight_2b",
        "question": "But now I also deliver and refill high-energy phosphor to structures that need them.",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "High energy?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "plight",
        "question": "Y'know, the super concentrated glowy stuff they had to process in factories, it's what powers most of this city's stuff.",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Oooh!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "plight_why",
        "question": "I haven't slept in so long...",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "When will the robots get fixed?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "plight_worry",
        "question": "But they seem REALLY concerned about something else lately...",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Oh?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "plight_worry",
        "question": "...Never a good sign when even the smart folks are worried.",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "This city is very big!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "plight_2",
        "question": "First there was the refugees from the Barrens, and now more Glen folks are moving in too.",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Oh?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "plight_worry",
        "question": "We get more of that here than anywhere else, apparently.",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "I noticed..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "plight_2b",
        "question": "Which is good, since there isn't much solid land here in the first place.",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Can you tell me about the library?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "plight",
        "question": ".......",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "......."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "mason",
        "question": "...On a larger scale than this, I mean.",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Oh! You're a gardener, right?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "mason",
        "question": "Yup!",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Do you... happen to have any dirt?For growing plants, I mean!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "mason",
        "question": "Yup!Do you need some?",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Yes!I'm supposed to plant this seed left behind by a plant lady..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "mason",
        "question": "Here, take this whole bag!",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Thanks!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "mason",
        "question": "Hello there!",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "You have a lot of plants!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "mason",
        "question": "Feel free to ask me about them!",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "A small garden trowel. The handle part is shaped like... an owl?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "mason",
        "question": "That's a phosphor tree.",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Oh! Like the ones we saw in the glen!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "mason",
        "question": "Although these trees are composed of a woody tissue, they're closer to grass, anatomy-wise.",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "...So the branches are actually leaves?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "mason",
        "question": "What's interesting about these plants is the amount of phosphor sap they can generate.",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Phosphor... that's the glowy stuff, right?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "mason",
        "question": "...well, let's talk about something else.",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "The pots are labeled with different species names."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "mason",
        "question": "I'd love to chat with him, if I run into him again!",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Black clovers."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "mason",
        "question": "That golden color is quite something, no?",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "It's wheat!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "mason",
        "question": "Well, doesn't it look nice?",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "I guess!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "mason",
        "question": "...Or in a flowerpot.",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "A small tree with leaves."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "mason",
        "question": "And the ones you do see are pretty much all raised artificially by people like me, mostly for nostalgia purposes.",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Cactus."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "mason",
        "question": "Cactus.",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "Cactus."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "ling_smile",
        "question": "Hang in there.You can do it.",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "Thanks..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "ling_shock",
        "question": "Oh hey, you're back!Did you manage to fix the elevator?",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Mhm!Playerand I went to the surface already!And..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "ling",
        "question": "We sure do!",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Wait! I don't have any money...Maybe I can help you wash dishes...or... something?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "ling",
        "question": "Here, why don't you take a seat?I'll go fry some up for you.",
        "response_character": "niko_pancakes",
        "response": "Pancakes..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "ling",
        "question": "No problem!You looked really hungry.",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Yeah... I thought this would be my last chance to eat something before I go in the Tower."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "ling",
        "question": "So... I guess pancakes are your favorite food?",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Mhm!..well, almost!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "ling_smile",
        "question": "Oh, wow, that sounds amazing!",
        "response_character": "niko_pancakes",
        "response": "They TASTE amazing!She always made them when I was feeling sad.Or lonely... or..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "ling_hm",
        "question": "And...I'm sure you'll be able to save the world!You're a tough kid, you managed to get this far already, right?",
        "response_character": "niko_distressed_meow",
        "response": "Yeah...  but..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "ling",
        "question": "And you'll get to go home afterwards, right?",
        "response_character": "niko_less_sad",
        "response": "Right..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "ling_smile",
        "question": "...Hey, want some more pancakes?",
        "response_character": "niko_cry",
        "response": "It's ok.....I'll be fine."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "ling_smile",
        "question": "So... yeah!Thanks for coming by!",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Mhm! Thanks for listening.....AND for the pancakes!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "ling",
        "question": "Oh, hi there!",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Hello!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "ling_hm",
        "question": "Yeah, it's a really slow day...",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Do you think it's because the ground access elevator is broken?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "ling_oh",
        "question": "...I mean, it's an important job, but nothing is worth that amount of stress, I think...",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "What does he do?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "ling",
        "question": "I can cook something for you, if you want...",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "It's alright, thank you!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "ling_smile",
        "question": "Well, don't be afraid to ask if you do get hungry!I'll be happy to make something for you!",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "It's an empty coffee tin."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "watcher",
        "question": "Please, do cherish it.",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "I will!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "watcher",
        "question": "It's not healthy for children such as yourself to stay up at this hour.",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "...Really?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "watcher",
        "question": "With the sun gone, the night never seems to end.",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Then... how can you tell?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "watcher",
        "question": "With the sun gone, the night never seems to end.",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Then... How can you tell?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "plight",
        "question": "Anyway, it was nice meeting you....uh",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Niko!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "plight",
        "question": "Gotta run now!",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "He seems in a hurry..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "bookbot",
        "question": "[IF YOU HAVE AN INQUIRY. PLEASE APPROACH FROM THE FRONT.]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "I'm good, thanks!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "bookbot",
        "question": "[LIBRARY CARD REQUIRED FOR FURTHER ACCESS.]",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "I know, I know..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "bookbot",
        "question": "[LIBRARY CARD REQUIRED FOR FURTHER ACCESS.]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Wait, what?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "bookbot",
        "question": "[LIBRARY CARD REQUIRED FOR FURTHER ACCESS.]",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "I don't have a library card, though!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "bookbot",
        "question": "[ALLOW ME TO CALL HER.]",
        "response_character": "niko_huh",
        "response": ". . ."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "bookbot",
        "question": "[SHE IS NOT PICKING UP.]",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "I figured..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "bookbot",
        "question": "[LETTING YOU THROUGH WITHOUT A LIBRARY CARD IS AGAINST MY PROGRAMMING.]",
        "response_character": "niko_what",
        "response": "Wh-"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "bookbot",
        "question": "[I HAVE NOT BEEN TAMED.]",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "Sigh..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "bookbot",
        "question": "[BUT THE SYMBOL ON THE COVER IS OF IMPORTANCE]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Oh?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "bookbot",
        "question": "[WOULD YOU LIKE ME TO CALL HER?]",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "Please don't."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "bookbot",
        "question": "[YOU CANNOT USE THIS CARD.]",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "Bummer..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "bookbot",
        "question": "[PHOTO IS MISSING.]",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "...why did I do that."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "bookbot",
        "question": "[HAVE A NICE DAY, MISS KIP.]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Yup, that's... totally me."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "bookbot",
        "question": "[HAVE A NICE DAY, MISS KIP.]",
        "response_character": "niko_what",
        "response": "..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "bookbot",
        "question": "[...FOR PEOPLE WHO ALREADY POSSESS CARDS.]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Ah."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "bookbot",
        "question": "[ALLOW ME TO CALL HER-",
        "response_character": "niko_surprised",
        "response": "Don't!!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "bookbot",
        "question": "[HAVE A NICE DAY, MISS KIP.]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Yup, that's... totally me."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "bookbot",
        "question": "[THE HEAD LIBRARIAN, GEORGE, IS IN THE ARCHIVAL ROOM UPSTAIRS.]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Excuse me!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "bookbot",
        "question": "[WELCOME.]",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "When I first entered the city, a big robot told me to look for a library on the surface!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "bookbot",
        "question": "[AFFIRMATIVE.]",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Oh, goody!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "bookbot",
        "question": "[SHE IS NOT PICKING UP.]",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Is she...not here?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "bookbot",
        "question": "[...FOR SEVERAL DAYS.]",
        "response_character": "niko_what",
        "response": "Yikes!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "bookbot",
        "question": "[LEAVING THIS POST IS NOT IN MY PROGRAMMING.]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Then...can I go myself?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "bookbot",
        "question": "[THE ARCHIVAL ROOM IS ACCESSIBLE THROUGH THE STAIRWELL BEHIND ME.]",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Gotcha, thanks!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george1",
        "question": "Oh, do you need George to tell you what to do again?",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Yes please!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george1",
        "question": "With those three items at hand, you must stand in the room, andPlayerwill do something about floor patterns and windows.",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Alright... thank you!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george1_smile",
        "question": "I have finished the daunting task of translating this journal!",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Oh! That was fast!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george1",
        "question": "Anyway, I made you a line-by-line transcript.It looks like this journal might be meant forPlayer.",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Oh?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george1",
        "question": "The rest of the pages are torn out.You didn't do this, did you?",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "No!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george1",
        "question": "A shame! I was wondering what \"window\" was supposed to mean.Ah well, I guessPlayerwill have to figure out that one.",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Right..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george1",
        "question": "It means you need items containing yellow phosphor, the rarest of the phosphors...said to absorb sunlight for the longest time and never fade out.",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Oh!I do have a piece of amber and a feather, they're both glowing yellow..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george1",
        "question": "Fear not! For George, collector of rare artifacts... will assist you!Here.",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Oh...It looks... ..like you?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george1_smile",
        "question": "Now you'll never forget my face!The face... of knowledge.",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Ah, thank you!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george1",
        "question": "Yes, even someone as great as I must put the proper thought and care into a task like this.",
        "response_character": "niko_yawn",
        "response": "*yawn*..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george1",
        "question": "Guest room's in the attic down the hall, in case you forgot.",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Oh!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george1",
        "question": "...this will take some time, however.",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "I see...*yawn*..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george1_hm",
        "question": "Oh? What's this?You are sleepy?",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "A little...."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george1",
        "question": "...Guest room's in the attic down the hall.",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "So...."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george2",
        "question": "Since you already have those, you must stand in the room and wait forPlayerto do something about floor patterns and windows.",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Alright... that makes sense.Thank you!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george2_grr",
        "question": "THERE. FINALLY...the translation is done.",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Oh!That was faster than I thought!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george2_grr",
        "question": "Well, YEAH!You've been asleep for hours!",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "Oh..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george2_sigh",
        "question": "Anyway...It looks like this journal was meant forPlayer.",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Oh?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george2_grr",
        "question": "Did YOU do this???",
        "response_character": "niko_huh",
        "response": "No!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george2_sigh",
        "question": "Then you're on your own, kid. I'm not sure what \"window\" means here.MaybePlayerwill have to figure out that one.",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Right..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george2_sigh",
        "question": "Y'know, stuff that glows yellow.",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Oh!I do have a piece of amber and a feather!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george2_grr",
        "question": "And they're super rare so it's not like you're just gonna find something like that on the ground.",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "Right..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george2",
        "question": "Here. You can have this.",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Oh...It looks... ..kinda like you?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george2_grr",
        "question": "What? Never seen dice before?",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "No! I mean yes!I mean, it's just..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george2_grr",
        "question": "So... yeah.Need anything else?",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "I'm good, thank you!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george2_grr",
        "question": "...Off you go, then.Don't screw this up, okay?",
        "response_character": "niko_yawn",
        "response": "*yawn*..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george2_grr",
        "question": "Just go take a nap. Translating's gonna take a while anyway.",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Oh!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george2_grr",
        "question": "...oh.Of course... OF COURSE!!!",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Um..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george2_grr",
        "question": "Hey uh, kid...",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Niko!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george2_grr",
        "question": "Looks I'm gonna have to translate this for you.Might take a while.",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Alright...*yawn*..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george2_grr",
        "question": "I know that feel, kid.I haven't had a good night's sleep in weeks!",
        "response_character": "niko_yawn",
        "response": "*yawn*..... that's ...not good..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george3_sad",
        "question": "And...since you have the three items... you need to stand in the room, andPlayerwill do something about floor patterns and windows...",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "That makes sense, thank you!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george3_sigh",
        "question": "It's done...",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "That was fast! Thank you!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george3_sigh",
        "question": "You've just been sleeping....",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "Right."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george3_worry",
        "question": "Anyway... he... this person... wrote this journal forPlayer... I think...",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Oh?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george3_worry",
        "question": "A lot of the pages were torn out...Do you know what happened?",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "No!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george3_sad",
        "question": "Ah... I don't know what \"window\" is supposed to mean.MaybePlayerwill know...",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Right..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george3_worry",
        "question": "But they're really rare...",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Ooooh.I have a piece of amber and a feather, they're both glowing yellow..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george3_sigh",
        "question": "...Here, you can have this.",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Oh...It looks... ..like you?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george3_cry",
        "question": "THE WORLD IS GONNA DIE AND IT'S GONNA BE MY FAULT!",
        "response_character": "niko_what",
        "response": "..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george3_sad",
        "question": "Are you sure?",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Yeah! Thank you for helping us, by the way!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george3_cry",
        "question": "I'm working as fast as I can...!!",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "No worries!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george3_sad",
        "question": "If you forgot, the guest room is down the hall and upstairs...",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Excuse me!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george3_sad",
        "question": "Oh...Oh, dear....",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Hm?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george3_worry",
        "question": "There's no mistake... I have to translate it.",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Oh, no problem!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george3_sad",
        "question": "I'll try my best, but... It probably won't be very fast.",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "That's okay.*yawn*..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george3_worry",
        "question": "Oh dear, are you... tired?",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "A little...."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george4_golly",
        "question": "Oh, do you need me to explain again?",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Yes please!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george4_smile",
        "question": "That's all there is to it!",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Thank you!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george4",
        "question": "Heya! Had a good nap?",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Mhm!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george4",
        "question": "Goody!I finished translating the journal, by the way!",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Oh! That was fast!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george4_oops",
        "question": "Well, you were out for a while.Anyway, it looks like this journal might be meant forPlayer!",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Oh?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george4",
        "question": "Here, take a look yourself!",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Is that all?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george4",
        "question": "I...guess you don't know what happened to those?",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "Nope..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george4_oops",
        "question": "Aww... I was wondering what \"window\" was supposed to mean.Ah well, I guessPlayerwill have to figure out that one.",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Right..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george4_smile",
        "question": "That just means you need things that contain yellow phosphor!They glow for a long time!",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Ooh!I do have a piece of amber and a feather, they're both glowing yellow..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george4",
        "question": "Here, you can have this then!",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Oh...It looks..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george4_smile",
        "question": "Like me, right?",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Mhm!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george4_smile",
        "question": "Now you have a little keepsake from the library!",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Thank you!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george4_oops",
        "question": "Haha... it won't be done for a while, sorry!",
        "response_character": "niko_yawn",
        "response": "*yawn*..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george4_golly",
        "question": "Seriously, you should go take a nap before you overexert yourself!The guest room is in the attic down the hall, if you forgot!",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Oh! I do have this!I...think it's written in some sort of...words I don't recognize?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george4",
        "question": "And not just any book! Golly... where did you find this?",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "I woke up with it."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george4",
        "question": "I need to borrow this journal for a bit, okay?Gotta translate it!",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Oh, cool!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george4_oops",
        "question": "It... might take a while, though...",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "That's fine!*yawn*..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george4_golly",
        "question": "Gosh! You look really tired!",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "A little, yeah...."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george4",
        "question": "If you want, you can go take a nap!.. a catnap!",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george5",
        "question": "Oh! Would you like me to explain again?",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Yes please!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george5",
        "question": "...and then, you must stand in the room, andPlayerwill do something about floor patterns and windows.",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Ooo, makes sense, thank you!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george5_smile",
        "question": "Had a good nap, dear?",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Mhm!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george5",
        "question": "I have the translation ready for you now.It looks like this journal might be meant forPlayer.",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Oh?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george5_hmm",
        "question": "That is all there is to translate...Looks like the other pages have been torn out.",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Oh..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george5_hmm",
        "question": "Quite a shame! I was wondering what \"window\" was supposed to mean.Ah well, I guessPlayercan figure that one out!",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Right..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george5",
        "question": "That means the stuff containing yellow phosphor!They glow for a very long time, so people call them \"pieces of the sun\" sometimes!",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Oh!I do have a piece of amber and a feather, they're both glowing yellow..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george5",
        "question": "Very good, dear!And I can help you with the last one!",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Oh...It looks......like you?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george5_heh",
        "question": "I know! Isn't it silly?But now you'll have something to remind you of the library!",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Ah, thank you!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george5_smile",
        "question": "Good luck now, sweetie!I wish you safe travels!",
        "response_character": "niko_yawn",
        "response": "*yawn*..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george5_smile",
        "question": "Don't wear yourself out now, dear!The guest room is just down the hall to the right.",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Oh! I do have this book!I...think it's written in some sort of...words I don't recognize?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george5",
        "question": "Really now!May I take a closer look, dear?",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Here!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george5",
        "question": "Oh!Oh my! Where did you find this?",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "I woke up with it."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george5_hmm",
        "question": "Is it alright if I hold on to the journal for now, sweetheart?It might take a little while, I'm afraid!",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Go for it!*yawn*..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george5_smile",
        "question": "I think you deserve a nap, no?",
        "response_character": "niko_yawn",
        "response": "A nap does sounds nice..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george6_point",
        "question": "You look a lil' lost still. Want some hot tips?",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Yes please!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george6",
        "question": "Once you got 'em (which you do), just stand in the room, andPlayerwill do something about floor patterns and windows.",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Alright...Thank you!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george6_fingerguns",
        "question": "You're toooootally welcome!",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Well, I guess we'll be on our way?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george6",
        "question": "Just finished translating this book for ya!",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Oh! That was fast!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george6",
        "question": "By the by, it looks like this journal might be meant forPlayer.",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Oh?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george6",
        "question": "That's all, we juiced it!",
        "response_character": "niko_what",
        "response": "...juiced what?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george6_shrug",
        "question": "Rest of the pages are torn out.Do you know what happened here?",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "No!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george6_shrug",
        "question": "Bummer! I was hoping to figure out what he meant by saying \"window\" here.Guess we'll leave that up toPlayer, huh?",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Right..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george6_point",
        "question": "Oh! That's just stuff with yellow phosphor in 'em!The kind of stuff that glows forever, dude.",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Oh!I do have a piece of amber and a feather, they're both glowing yellow..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george6_point",
        "question": "But we coo'!I gotcha covered, lil' fella!Here ya go.",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Oh...It looks.....like you?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george6_fingerguns",
        "question": "The freshest face you've ever seen, ehhhhh?And it's all yours.",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Ah, thank you!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george6_fingerguns",
        "question": "You're toooootally welcome!",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Well, I guess we'll be on our way?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george6_shrug",
        "question": "Bruh, it's gonna take some time to make this book readable, know what I'm sayin'?",
        "response_character": "niko_yawn",
        "response": "*yawn*..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george6",
        "question": "Guest room's in the attic down the hall, FYI.",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Oh! I do have this book!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george6",
        "question": "Where'd you find this?",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "I woke up with it."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george6",
        "question": "I gotta translate this, man.Mind if I borrow this?",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Not at all!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george6",
        "question": "Sweeeeet.It's gon' take a while tho, you cool with that?",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "That's fine!*yawn*..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george6",
        "question": "Whoa dude, you look wiped, kiddo!",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "...Huh?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george6_point",
        "question": "You look totally tapped out, dude!",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "I look... what?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george6",
        "question": "You look like you're ready to take five, bruh!",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "...yeah I don't get it."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george6",
        "question": "So how do you like my books, bruh.",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "They're... nice?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george6_fingerguns",
        "question": "Eyyyyyy.",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Even the painting is books."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george2_stress",
        "question": "What? You wanna read them or something??",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": ""
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george5",
        "question": "There's a couple of picture books that you might be interested in!",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Oh!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george6_shrug",
        "question": "If you want, I mean.",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "There's a black clover symbol on the cover of this book."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george1_smile",
        "question": "A black clover is the mark of The Author!",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Oh?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george1_hm",
        "question": "Since he never entrusted me or anyone else with his name, we identify his works by the mark.",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "So...he wrote ALL of these books?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george2_grr",
        "question": "That's just how The Author marks his work!",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Oh?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george2",
        "question": "He's never even told me his name!",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Wait, so he wrote ALL of these books?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george3_sigh",
        "question": "I don't even know his name...",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Oh! So he wrote ALL of these books?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george4",
        "question": "A black clover symbol just means it's written by The Author.",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Oh?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george4_golly",
        "question": "He doesn't want to tell anyone his name. So he marks all his works with this symbol instead!",
        "response_character": "niko_pancakes",
        "response": "He wrote ALL of these books?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george5",
        "question": "The black clover is sort of The Author's name, you see!",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Oh?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george5_hmm",
        "question": "Actually, we don't know his name! He just uses a clover to mark his works is all.",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "So... he wrote ALL of these books?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george6",
        "question": "That's like, just what The Author calls himself.",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Oh?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george6_shrug",
        "question": "He don't tell anyone his name. He just uses this symbol on his works so we know it's him.",
        "response_character": "niko_pancakes",
        "response": "...he wrote ALL of these books?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george1_smug",
        "question": "They all have me to thank, of course.",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Oh? What does he write about?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george2_stress",
        "question": "DON'T TOUCH THAT I HAVE TO FINISH THIS BY THE END OF THE WEEK.",
        "response_character": "niko_what",
        "response": "Oh, sorry..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george2_stress",
        "question": "PEOPLE ARE LITERALLY LINING UP TO READ HIS BOOKS!",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Oh? What does he write about?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george3",
        "question": "People would even wait in line to loan a copy....",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Oh? What does he write about?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george4",
        "question": "We literally have people lining up to read them!",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Oh? What does he write about?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george5_smile",
        "question": "You might be a little too young to understand them, but the older kids love them!",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Oh? What does he write about?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george6_point",
        "question": "I better up my game, dude.  Peeps are lining up to read his books!",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Oh? What does he write about?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george6",
        "question": "Gotta respect that.",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "These boxes are full of loose papers and notebooks."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george1_smug",
        "question": "I am in charge of publishing all of his books that everyone loves!",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Wow!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george1",
        "question": "The box of manuscripts just seems to be growing on its own!",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "These boxes are full of loose papers and notebooks."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george2_sigh",
        "question": "That's what books look like before they get published, kid.",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "I see!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george2_stress",
        "question": "WHAT IS EVEN HAPPENING!",
        "response_character": "niko_huh",
        "response": "Are you okay?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george2_no",
        "question": "NO!!!!!!",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "These boxes are full of loose papers and notebooks."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george3_sigh",
        "question": "You just had to remind me...",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "What's wrong?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george3_sad",
        "question": "The author hasn't shown up lately, nor has he sent me any new manuscripts...",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Oh?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george3_sad",
        "question": "The pile seems to just keep growing...",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "These boxes are full of loose papers and notebooks."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george4_omg",
        "question": "That guy works really fast!",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "I see..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george4_oops",
        "question": "Golly, you think I'm going bonkers?",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "These boxes are full of loose papers and notebooks."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george5_smile",
        "question": "I see you've taken an interest to the manuscripts!",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "What are they for?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george5_heh",
        "question": "I guess now it just means I get a little more breathing room, hohoho!",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "That's good!..right?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george6_point",
        "question": "But you know what's weird?",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "What?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george6_shrug",
        "question": "...Have I really been slackin' that much?",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "It's a bookshelf."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george1_smug",
        "question": "Caught wind of my genius and couldn't help but come see for yourself, eh?",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Um-"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george1_smile",
        "question": "What else could you ~possibly~ want?",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Actually... I need your help!Can you tell me what I need to do?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george1_hm",
        "question": "...Believe you're supposed to go in the Tower!",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "That's what I said...But how, exactly?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george1_smug",
        "question": "Then know that I, George, am fluent in several dead languages!",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "I...see!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george2_NO",
        "question": "I don't care if you're the Messiah, manners are still a thing!",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "I'm... sorry?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george2",
        "question": "Well? Are you just here to apologize?",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "...Yes?I mean, no!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george2",
        "question": "Seriously? You haven't figured that one out yet?",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "I don't know how to get in!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george2_grr",
        "question": "Would like to, though.",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "I see..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george3_sad",
        "question": "Siiiiigh.",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Um... hi?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george3_sigh",
        "question": "...Hi.",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Are you alright?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george3_sad",
        "question": "....",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "...."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george3_worry",
        "question": "Can I... help you...",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Yeah!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george3_cry",
        "question": "We're all gonna dieeeeeee....",
        "response_character": "niko_what",
        "response": "Um..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george3",
        "question": "Oh, I know there's a small room you can go in, but...Everybody knows that!",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "I see..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george4_omg",
        "question": "I'm soooo happy I actually get to meet you! <3",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "It's nice to meet you too, miss!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george4",
        "question": "So! Are you here to check out the archives?I can give you a tour!",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Actually...I need your help!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george4",
        "question": "Yup!",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Do you know how I can get in?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george4_golly",
        "question": "But I haven't read anything like that before...Sorry!",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Ah..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george5_aww",
        "question": "And also, the cutest darn thing I have ever seen!",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "U- um...Thank you!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george5_smile",
        "question": "Can I help you with anything, sweetie?",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Mhm!I want to know what I should do next!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george5_heh",
        "question": "Not even silly ol' me, who spent her entire life reading books about the world...",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Ah..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george6",
        "question": "Hey, lil' fella!",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Hello!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george6_fingerguns",
        "question": "Eyyyyyy.",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Um, thanks?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george6",
        "question": "So like, what up?Can I getcha anything?",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Yeah! I heard you can help me!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george6_shrug",
        "question": "Nothin' in my collection fits the description, tho.",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Ah..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "kelvin",
        "question": "[You have been here for a while...][Are you sure you do not wish to stay?]",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "I'm good, thanks for offering though!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "kelvin",
        "question": "[They found me on their own.][So I stay here now.]",
        "response_character": "niko2",
        "response": "Ah...Well, it's good that you're not alone, at least!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "kelvin",
        "question": "[We are not like people, we are typically unable to feel loneliness.]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Right..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "kelvin",
        "question": "[One of them even lives here.]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "I see..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "kelvin",
        "question": "[This was my original purpose.]",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "...watching cats?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "kelvin",
        "question": "[Warmth.]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Oooh!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "kelvin",
        "question": "[Oh,  you look tired.][Do you wish to rest?]",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "I can't sleep now!Playerand I got stuff to do!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "kelvin",
        "question": "[Are you lost?]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Me?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "kelvin",
        "question": "[Do you wish to join us?]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Join... your cats?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "kelvin",
        "question": "[Yes.]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "But I'm not a cat..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "kelvin",
        "question": "[You have cat eyes.]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "My eyes are normal people eyes..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "kelvin",
        "question": "[Your hat is shaped like a cat.]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "But I'm just a person!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "kelvin",
        "question": "[I protect lost people as well.]",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Thanks! But I'm not lost though!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "shepherd",
        "question": "We meet again.",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Hello..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "shepherd",
        "question": "even... in your heart.",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "...okay."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "shepherd",
        "question": "They would have... flip-flops.",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "...I don't get it."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "shepherd",
        "question": "...but we kept having page faults due to rams getting out of the server room.",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "...what?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "shepherd",
        "question": "404 ram not found.",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "I have no idea what any of that meant."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "shepherd",
        "question": "That one is...  Read-Only.",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "I...see..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "shepherd",
        "question": "...RAMen?",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "shepherd",
        "question": "Come to think of it, we're probably out of ramen.",
        "response_character": "niko_what",
        "response": "Ow!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "shepherd",
        "question": "A STATIC shock!",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "Don't \"baa\" at me..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "rue_dark",
        "question": "Not now...",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Um..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "rue_dark",
        "question": "But... can you promise me something?",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Huh?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "rue_dark",
        "question": "...please do.",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Er...What... do you mean by that?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "rue",
        "question": "We will meet again.",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "...?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "rue_talk",
        "question": "So you found a way back after all.",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Eh?But I've never been here before..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "rue_talk",
        "question": "Have you... met the others?",
        "response_character": "niko2",
        "response": "...others?You're the only fox I've seen..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "rue",
        "question": "It's not time.",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "...?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "rue_smile",
        "question": "Hello, Niko.",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Hello..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "rue",
        "question": "But...I said it was not time...",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "...?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "rue_sad",
        "question": "You will probably not remember my name in a while...But I would still like to know yours.",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "I'm... not sure what you're talking about."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "rue_sad",
        "question": "It may be this way for a while, actually.",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "...?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "rue",
        "question": "...But in time, that will change.",
        "response_character": "niko2",
        "response": "The... sun?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "rue_smile",
        "question": "Playercan see this, right?",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "...yeah?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "rue_smile",
        "question": "...Guess I got used to your company, after all.",
        "response_character": "niko2",
        "response": "...pardon?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "rue",
        "question": "Do not worry. Carry on.",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Playerand I fixed the camera!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "plight_2",
        "question": "Well, good luck...",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "You too! With the lamp."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "plight",
        "question": "Hey, you lookin for something?",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "Yeah... I need to go find a library card now...Any idea where I can get one?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "plight",
        "question": "From... the... library?",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "I tried that already!The person in charge wasn't here."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "plight",
        "question": "They might help you...",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "He looks busy..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "plight_2",
        "question": "You, uh... doing okay?",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Yup!What are you doing?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "plight_worry",
        "question": "(oH GOODNESS GRACIOUS DID THE MESSIAH AND LITERALLY GOD THEMSELF JUST BREAK INTO MY HOUSE.)",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Oh! Was that... your..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "plight_worry",
        "question": "(IT KEEPS HAPPENING.)",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "...sorry about breaking into your house.We didn't actually break anything, but..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "plight_worry",
        "question": "I wouldn't have been able to fix that machine anyway...",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "A streetlamp!This one seems taller than the others..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "kip",
        "question": "You should hold on to that amber, okay?",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "I will!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "kip2",
        "question": "How...did you get this?",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "This robot lady in the Barrens gave it to me!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "kip_pout",
        "question": "I even based her on myself so I'll KNOW it works!",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Break...through?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "kip_pout",
        "question": "...a robot that isn't bound by its own code.",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Oh!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "kip_sigh",
        "question": "Scariest day of my life, tell you what!",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "...rogue?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "kip_sad",
        "question": "She won't even answer my letters...",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "I'm sorry..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "kip",
        "question": "You should hold on to that amber, okay?",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "I will!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "kip",
        "question": "Is there anything else you need?",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Nope!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "kip",
        "question": "Can I help you with anything else?",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Yeah..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "kip",
        "question": "You'll have to ask the library for that!",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "I tried..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "kip_huh",
        "question": "I'm sorry you caught her on a bad day!",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Aw..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "kip",
        "question": "It won't be hard for me to get another one.",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Wow, thanks!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "kip_wink",
        "question": "...unless I tape a photo of my face to your face!",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Um-"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "kip_wink",
        "question": "You've been walking all over the world, huh?",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "M-hm!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "kip_huh",
        "question": "Do you get really tired sometimes?",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "Kinda..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "kip",
        "question": "Even with the sun gone, the world is still a beautiful place.",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "What did the world look like with the sun?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "kip_sigh",
        "question": "...y'know, it's kind of embarassing to admit how little of it I have actually seen.",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "...oh?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "kip_sigh",
        "question": "They're the ones exploring the world, I just write down the data, crunch numbers, generate graphs...",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Right... I've been seeing robots everywhere!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "kip",
        "question": "But I know someone who still does his research firsthand!",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Oh?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "kip_huh",
        "question": "I mean, he outright built a machine that could fly!Something we all thought was not physically possible!",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Oh! That's..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "kip_sigh",
        "question": "Or, more specifically, coding them.",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "How come?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "kip_heh",
        "question": "...ah. It's been a while since we last talked.He must be busy with his books now, yeah.",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "...Hello?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "kip_heh",
        "question": "Sorry about the weird... security measures.",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "It's okay!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "kip",
        "question": "So... can I help you with anything?",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Yeah..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "kip",
        "question": "You'll have to ask the library for that!",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "I tried..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "kip_huh",
        "question": "I'm sorry you caught her on a bad day!",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Aw..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "kip",
        "question": "It won't be hard for me to get another one.",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Wow, thanks!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "kip_wink",
        "question": "...unless I tape a photo of my face to your face!",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Um-"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "kip_heh",
        "question": "Sorry about the weird... security measures.",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "It's okay!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "kip",
        "question": "So... can I help you with anything?",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Yeah, where's the library?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "kip2",
        "question": "The fastest route is where you take the shortcut through the backalley, but...",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "I think that's how we got here, actually!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "kip",
        "question": "You'll find it eventually!",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Thank you!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "kip_wink",
        "question": "Never know when you need to glitter things up, right?",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Oh! Are you sure?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "kip_wink",
        "question": "Yeah! I have tons of those!",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Thank you!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "credits",
        "question": "Thanks for Playing!",
        "response_character": "niko4",
        "response": "They're in the door..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "green_gatekeeper",
        "question": "[TH#e.%%GAT;E IS C//L OSED UNT#IL FU#RT|HER N%OTICE.]",
        "response_character": "niko3",
        "response": "..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "maize_stress",
        "question": "Hello...",
        "response_character": "niko2",
        "response": "I... um...have something to ask of you..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "maize_thisisfine",
        "question": "...yes?",
        "response_character": "niko5",
        "response": "It looks like most of the bridges around the Glen are broken, and..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "maize_thisisfine",
        "question": "...would you...like me to fix them?",
        "response_character": "niko2",
        "response": "Yeah! Is it possible?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "maize_stress",
        "question": "...an undertaking.",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "Ah..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "maize_thisisfine",
        "question": "I... intend to use the last of my strength.",
        "response_character": "niko3",
        "response": "..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "maize_strain",
        "question": "...please stand back.",
        "response_character": "niko_shock",
        "response": "..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "maize_thisisfine",
        "question": "...... you're...here to see me...?",
        "response_character": "niko_shock",
        "response": "...what... happened to you?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "maize_stress",
        "question": "...I.... need to concentrate",
        "response_character": "niko2",
        "response": "...?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "maize_strain",
        "question": "...that's why... the vines...",
        "response_character": "niko2",
        "response": "...you're... making the vines grow..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "maize_stress",
        "question": "My powers... the best I could do. Yes.",
        "response_character": "niko3",
        "response": "That's..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "maize_strain",
        "question": "...makes me strong....vines grow faster.",
        "response_character": "niko4",
        "response": "But..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "maize_stress",
        "question": "If I'm at ease... the vines might retreat.",
        "response_character": "niko4",
        "response": "..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "maize_thisisfine",
        "question": "The people deserve to live... even if just for another day...",
        "response_character": "niko4",
        "response": "..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "calamus_sad",
        "question": "I knew we'd lose our home eventually, but...I wasn't expecting it to happen so soon...",
        "response_character": "niko_shock",
        "response": "Oh jeez!Are you guys okay?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "calamus_sad",
        "question": "Yes, Alula, thank you.",
        "response_character": "niko3",
        "response": "It's... getting everywhere now... isn't it?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "calamus",
        "question": "Hm?",
        "response_character": "niko3",
        "response": "The squares... there are way more than before!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "calamus_speak",
        "question": "...last time?",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "....."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "calamus",
        "question": ".....",
        "response_character": "niko5",
        "response": "Uhh...othing!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "calamus_shame",
        "question": "Oh gosh! Would it not be rude to call you by name?",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "No worries, Calamus!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "calamus_shame",
        "question": "HOW DID YOU KNOW MY NAME!?",
        "response_character": "niko2",
        "response": "I... um... uh..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "alula",
        "question": "Riiiight?",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Y-yes! Of course!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "calamus",
        "question": "Ah... you were saying... about the gate?",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Oh, right!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "calamus_speak",
        "question": "Oh!The passage to the burial grounds?",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "That's the one!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "calamus",
        "question": "Not to mention, the burial grounds itself is pretty far from the city!",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "That's ok! I would still like to see it!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "calamus_smile",
        "question": "...please follow us.",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "It's a ball."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "calamus_shock",
        "question": "You looked like you were about to faint!",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "calamus",
        "question": "...oh?",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Earlier I was in the Barrens, and I...saw something like this too."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "calamus_speak",
        "question": "Like something a prophet would see!",
        "response_character": "niko2",
        "response": "I... guess?The robot lady I was with earlier had a fancy word for it, though..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "calamus",
        "question": "...huh?",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "When I had the vision back at the Barrens... the book started glowing too!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "alula_gasp",
        "question": "Where did you get that!!!",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Oh, uh... I had it with me when I woke up in this world!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "alula",
        "question": "...Except it's glowy!",
        "response_character": "niko2",
        "response": "...that's what the lady said too..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "calamus_shock",
        "question": "How did that boat get there?",
        "response_character": "niko_shock",
        "response": "..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "calamus_speak",
        "question": "Seriously?",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "The journal was glowing, so I wanted to take a closer look at it."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "calamus",
        "question": "Well...ifPlayermade the boat appear... it should be safe...",
        "response_character": "niko2",
        "response": "What... do you think,Player?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "calamus_smile",
        "question": "We can leave whenever you're ready.",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "It's a clover."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "alula_oh",
        "question": "Do you want to go back, Niko?",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "...Nah."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "cedric_talk",
        "question": "It's you!",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "cedric_smile",
        "question": "You are Niko, right?",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Mhm!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "cedric_hmm",
        "question": "You... um...",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "My name is Niko..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "cedric_smile",
        "question": "My name is Cedric.",
        "response_character": "niko2",
        "response": "Oh!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "cedric_hmm",
        "question": "Prototype had contacted me earlier, saying that you would be on your way to the city.",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "He did?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "cedric",
        "question": "He sent me a message after his memories were restored.",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Oh..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "cedric_sigh",
        "question": "...Turns out, that was a terrible idea.",
        "response_character": "niko2",
        "response": "Pick... us up?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "cedric_hmm",
        "question": "What...is a plane?",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "That thing behind you!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "cedric_talk",
        "question": "Oh! You mean the flying machine?",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "They're called planes in my world!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "cedric_sigh",
        "question": "...I did not realize they existed in other worlds...",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "...wait! Are you the friend that Calamus and Alula was talking about, then?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "cedric_talk",
        "question": "I think... they're meant to be friends with my father...in previous iterations of the...",
        "response_character": "niko2",
        "response": "...your father?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "cedric_talk",
        "question": "He was the original owner of the flying machine.....it's... one of his greatest inventions, actually.",
        "response_character": "niko_pancakes",
        "response": "YOUR DAD INVENTED PLANES???"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "cedric_hmm",
        "question": "...flying machine.",
        "response_character": "niko_pancakes",
        "response": "IT'S COOL EITHER WAY!!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "cedric_sigh",
        "question": "I had to make an emergency landing on this tiny island before I crashed into the city wall.",
        "response_character": "niko3",
        "response": "You almost crashed?That's terrible!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "cedric_hmm",
        "question": "...but I noticed some islands in the Glen are REALLY messed up now.",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "They are..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "cedric",
        "question": "Is he still back at the main islands?",
        "response_character": "niko3",
        "response": "Oh... actually..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "cedric_eek",
        "question": "No....",
        "response_character": "niko_distressed",
        "response": "..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "cedric_hmm",
        "question": "As long as I have this, I should be able to bring him back.",
        "response_character": "niko2",
        "response": "R-really?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "cedric",
        "question": "You need all three of us for the big door.",
        "response_character": "niko2",
        "response": "The...?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "cedric_hmm",
        "question": "But first thing's first, we need to find a way to go to the city.",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "Right...The city gate is kind of kaput now."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "cedric_hmm",
        "question": "I've isolated the issue with the machine, but I can't repair it with the stuff I have on hand.",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Oh? What's wrong with it?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "cedric",
        "question": "The c[2]batteryc[0] in the engine is dead, and the engine has some c[2]gearsc[0] that need to be replaced.",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "...Do you think you'll be able to fix it ifPlayerand I help you find those things?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "cedric_sigh",
        "question": "...I'm not sure if you'll be able to find anything so specialized here.",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "We'll try anyway!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "cedric3",
        "question": "I honestly wasn't expecting it...",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "It's from the generator on one of the islands."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "cedric_talk",
        "question": "The research station?",
        "response_character": "niko2",
        "response": "Yeah."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "cedric_smile",
        "question": "...we can always just give it back later.",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "Alright..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "cedric_hmm",
        "question": "We still need a few c[2]gearsc[0] to put this engine back together.Please do what you must to find some.",
        "response_character": "niko2",
        "response": "We found a battery..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "cedric3",
        "question": "I honestly wasn't expecting it...",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "We found this one in the Barrens.It wasn't working at first, butPlayerand I managed to fix it!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "cedric_smile",
        "question": "...it's good that you thought to bring it with you then.",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Yup!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "cedric_hmm",
        "question": "We still need a few c[2]gearsc[0] to put this engine back together.Please do what you must to find some.",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "We found a music box!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "cedric_hmm",
        "question": "This looks like one of the ones that my father made.",
        "response_character": "niko_pancakes",
        "response": "YOUR DAD MAKES MUSIC BOXES TOO?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "cedric_hmm",
        "question": "Where did you get this from, by the way?",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "A trader from the village gave it to me!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "cedric_sigh",
        "question": "Although it pains me to have to take it apart...",
        "response_character": "niko2",
        "response": "Oh... I'm sorry!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "cedric",
        "question": "We still need a c[3]batteryc[0] to get this engine running.Please do what you must to find one.",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "Sorry... I forgot..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "cedric",
        "question": "If you could find me the parts I need, I should be able to get this machine off the ground again.",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "We made it!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "calamus_sad",
        "question": "This is her grave...",
        "response_character": "niko3",
        "response": "Ah..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "calamus_sad",
        "question": "...It's still... hard, y'know?",
        "response_character": "niko4",
        "response": "..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "calamus",
        "question": "We're just about done here, so let us know when you want to go back to the ruins.",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Okay."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "calamus_heh",
        "question": "We... don't really use electricity in the Glen.",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "Ah."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "calamus_speak",
        "question": "Oh, but there are robots at the research station!If there's a battery anywhere, they'd know where it is.",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Gotcha, thanks!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "alula_speak",
        "question": "...hi Niko!",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Hi!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "alula_oh",
        "question": "...what were you looking for again?",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Gears?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "alula_speak",
        "question": "Gears!Didja find any of those?",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "No, but... I found this music box though!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "alula_gasp",
        "question": "Ooooh!",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Do you know where I could find some gears?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "alula",
        "question": "Gears?What's... that?",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "It's like... A metal circle thing with teeth!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "alula_speak",
        "question": "Haha, that sounds so silly!Like something Magpie would have!",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Magpie?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "alula_speak",
        "question": "I mean, he even keeps around broken glass and junk!",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "cedric_smile",
        "question": "Do you mind keeping me company?",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "How's it going?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "cedric_sigh",
        "question": "...and there's this bolt that keeps getting stuck, and...",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "...ah."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "cedric",
        "question": "We should be able to make it to the city by tonight.",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "If you say so..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "cedric_talk",
        "question": "Do you remember her from the last time you were in this world?",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "I..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "cedric_talk",
        "question": "She is a fox.",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "...Rue?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "cedric_talk",
        "question": "You've met?",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "I... think so..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "cedric_talk",
        "question": "You've met Rue?",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "The memories are still realy blurry, though..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "cedric_sigh",
        "question": "I see...",
        "response_character": "niko2",
        "response": "Oh, um..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "cedric_talk",
        "question": "Even if she IS the least hidden one of us...",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "My memories are still realy blurry, though..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "cedric_sigh",
        "question": "I see...",
        "response_character": "niko_upset",
        "response": "....sigh."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "cedric2",
        "question": "...",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "Proto also told me to not ask anyone in the world about this..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "cedric",
        "question": "...",
        "response_character": "niko3",
        "response": "...How do YOU know?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "cedric_hmm",
        "question": "...well...",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "I'm not sure what to even believe anymore..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "cedric_sigh",
        "question": "The last chance for him to fix everything.",
        "response_character": "niko2",
        "response": "Your father... is involved in the World Machine?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "cedric2",
        "question": "Thankfully, he gave you the disk just in time.",
        "response_character": "niko3",
        "response": "So... what happened to him anyway?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "cedric_hmm",
        "question": "Well, you know how the simulation works, right?",
        "response_character": "niko_upset2",
        "response": "How everything...is code....?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "cedric3",
        "question": "It took him forever to develop the current, much more stable version.",
        "response_character": "niko4",
        "response": "...you're making it sound like... your dad built the simulation himself..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "cedric_sigh",
        "question": "Yeah...",
        "response_character": "niko4",
        "response": "But... how?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "cedric2",
        "question": "That's...um...ot really what happened.",
        "response_character": "niko3",
        "response": "So... what happened?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "cedric_sigh2",
        "question": "...like I said, you shouldn't concern yourself with...",
        "response_character": "niko_distressed",
        "response": "..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "cedric4",
        "question": "...with",
        "response_character": "niko_distressed",
        "response": "....."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "cedric3",
        "question": "Did Prototype.... ever tell you about the old world?",
        "response_character": "niko4",
        "response": "..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "cedric_sigh",
        "question": "Our home world....the \"real\" world... was actually destroyed a long time ago.",
        "response_character": "niko_shock",
        "response": "..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "cedric4",
        "question": "In fact, the messiah would not even have been born before our world ended.",
        "response_character": "niko3",
        "response": "..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "cedric4",
        "question": "...after a heavy amount of modification and an added narrative, my father was able to convert the entire structure into code.",
        "response_character": "niko4",
        "response": "..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "cedric_sigh2",
        "question": "...but as you can see, even that's breaking down.",
        "response_character": "niko2",
        "response": "Ah..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "cedric_sigh",
        "question": "...waiting for a willing operator to install it onto their own hardware.",
        "response_character": "niko3",
        "response": "...Player?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "cedric",
        "question": "The operator...Player.... would then generate the universe using the code, becoming god in the process.",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "So...Playerwas the living person you needed to borrow?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "cedric",
        "question": "That.... would be you.",
        "response_character": "niko3",
        "response": "But why me?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "cedric_talk",
        "question": "It's you!",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "cedric_smile",
        "question": "You are Niko, correct?",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Mhm!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "cedric_smile",
        "question": "My name is Cedric.",
        "response_character": "niko2",
        "response": "Oh!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "cedric_hmm",
        "question": "Proto had contacted me earlier, saying that you would be on your way to the city.",
        "response_character": "niko2",
        "response": "...Proto?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "cedric",
        "question": "He sent me a message after his memories were restored.",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Oh..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "cedric_sigh",
        "question": "...Turns out, that was not a smart move.",
        "response_character": "niko2",
        "response": "Transport... directly?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "cedric_talk",
        "question": "...air...plane?I have no idea what that is.",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "That thing behind you!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "cedric_talk",
        "question": "Oh!You mean the flying machine?",
        "response_character": "niko2",
        "response": "I...guess you can call it that."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "cedric_sigh",
        "question": "...I did not realize they existed in other worlds...",
        "response_character": "niko2",
        "response": "...wait a minute! are you the friend that Calamus and Alula was talking about, then?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "cedric_smile",
        "question": "...it's... one of his greatest inventions, actually.",
        "response_character": "niko_pancakes",
        "response": "YOUR DAD INVENTED AIRPLANES???"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "cedric2",
        "question": "It's a flying machine!",
        "response_character": "niko_pancakes",
        "response": "IT'S COOL EITHER WAY!!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "cedric_sigh",
        "question": "I had to make an emergency landing on this tiny island before I crashed into the city wall.",
        "response_character": "niko3",
        "response": "Your almonst crashed?That's terrible!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "cedric_hmm",
        "question": "...I noticed some islands in the Glen are REALLY messed up now.",
        "response_character": "niko3",
        "response": "Looks like it..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "cedric3",
        "question": "Is he still back at the main islands?",
        "response_character": "niko3",
        "response": "Oh... actually..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "cedric_eek",
        "question": "No!!",
        "response_character": "niko_distressed",
        "response": "..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "cedric_hmm",
        "question": "As long as I have this, I should be able to bring him back.",
        "response_character": "niko2",
        "response": "R-really?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "cedric",
        "question": "You need all three of us to find the ending.",
        "response_character": "niko2",
        "response": "The...?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "cedric_hmm",
        "question": "But first thing's first, we need to find a way to go to the city.",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "Right...The city gate is kind of kaput now."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "cedric_hmm",
        "question": "I've isolated the issue with the machine, but I can't repair it with the stuff I have on hand.",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Oh? What's wrong with it?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "cedric",
        "question": "The c[2]batteryc[0] in the engine basically imploded, and the rest of the engine has some c[2]gearsc[0] missing.",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "...Do you think you'll be able to fix it ifPlayerand I helped you find those things?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "cedric_sigh",
        "question": "...I'm not sure if you'll be able to find anything so specialized here.",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "We'll try anyway!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "cedric2",
        "question": "...flying machine!",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Right."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "calamus",
        "question": "We're just about done here, so let us know when you want to go back to the ruins.",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Okay."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "calamus_heh",
        "question": "We... don't really use electricity in the Glen.",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "Ah."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "calamus_speak",
        "question": "Oh, but there are robots at the research station!If there's a battery anywhere, they'd know where it is.",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Gotcha, thanks!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "alula_oh",
        "question": "...what were you looking for again?",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Gears?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "alula_speak",
        "question": "Gears!Didja find any of those?",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "No, but... I found this music box though!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "alula_gasp",
        "question": "Ooooh!",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Do you know where I could find some gears?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "alula",
        "question": "Gears?What's... that?",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "It's like... A metal circle thing with teeth!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "alula_speak",
        "question": "Haha, that sounds so silly!Like something Magpie would have!",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Magpie?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "alula_speak",
        "question": "I mean, he even keeps around broken glass and junk!",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "cedric",
        "question": "We can leave in the next five minutes, if you are ready.",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "...alright."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "cedric_sigh2",
        "question": "The world means a lot to him, you know...",
        "response_character": "niko2",
        "response": "So... how does flying... work?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "cedric_talk",
        "question": "...wait, don't these machines already exist in your world?You should already know what to expect...",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "Not really..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "cedric_smile",
        "question": "It takes a few minutes of getting used to, but it's not that bad once you are in the air.",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "I'll... try."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "calamus_shock",
        "question": "The boat is gone!",
        "response_character": "niko3",
        "response": "What?!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "calamus_speak",
        "question": "It looks like they're headed in this direction!",
        "response_character": "niko3",
        "response": "That's..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "cedric_sigh",
        "question": "Then... it is of priority that I take you to the city first, Niko",
        "response_character": "niko2",
        "response": "But what about them...?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "cedric3",
        "question": "I will be back here in an hour, so please wait for me until then.",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "You guys sure you'll be fine here?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "calamus_speak",
        "question": "The squares are still moving pretty slowly for now...",
        "response_character": "niko2",
        "response": "Alright, then..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "cedric_smile",
        "question": "Alright!",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Do you know where I could find a battery for a flying machine?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "magpie",
        "question": "Also ask him if he has any more music boxes for trading.",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Will do!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "magpie_smile",
        "question": "Managed to grab some of my favorite things before I left, though!",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Oh! Uh..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "magpie",
        "question": "I do have this box thing that you can wind up and play a song.",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "That's a music box!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "magpie_smile",
        "question": "Yeah!I bet there's lots of little metal bits in there!",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Oh! That might work!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "magpie_hm",
        "question": "But I'm not sure if I want to trade it away...It's one of my favorite things!",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "Aw..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "magpie",
        "question": "You need this to save the world, right?Take it.",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Ah! Thank you!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "alula",
        "question": "But I don't!",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Same!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "alula",
        "question": "But I don't!",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Same!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "calamus_unknown",
        "question": "Alula?Alula? Where did you go?",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Player, did you hear that?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "calamus_unknown",
        "question": "Alula!",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "I think it's coming from south-east of here."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "cedric_smile",
        "question": "Made it!",
        "response_character": "niko_pancakes",
        "response": "..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "cedric3",
        "question": "You...okay, there?",
        "response_character": "niko_pancakes",
        "response": "...That was the coolest thing I have ever done in my entire life."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "cedric_smile",
        "question": "Heheh... reactions from first-timers are always delightful to watch.",
        "response_character": "niko_pancakes",
        "response": "..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "cedric3",
        "question": "Yeah?",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "Thanks..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "cedric3",
        "question": "....What for?",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Flying!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "cedric_smile",
        "question": "You're... welcome?",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "And... for answering my questions back there, too..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "cedric",
        "question": "...",
        "response_character": "niko4",
        "response": "And... even if it's all just a machine, this world is still...ice..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "cedric",
        "question": "I need to go pick up the siblings too...",
        "response_character": "niko2",
        "response": "That's true... those two have been waiting for a while now..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "cedric_smile",
        "question": "Do you remember what to do to get to the surface?",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "I remember having to fix an elevator button!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "cedric_talk",
        "question": "Let's meet up here in an hour, okay?",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Got it!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "cedric_eek",
        "question": "...",
        "response_character": "niko_shock",
        "response": "No!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "cedric_eek",
        "question": "...",
        "response_character": "niko_shock",
        "response": "...they're... trapped on the island..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "cedric_sigh",
        "question": "Please give me the memory disk.",
        "response_character": "niko2",
        "response": "...alright..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "cedric",
        "question": "She will know what to do in the meantime.",
        "response_character": "niko2",
        "response": "Alright...What about you, though?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "cedric3",
        "question": "I'm going to bring Prototype back.",
        "response_character": "niko_surprised",
        "response": "WH-"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "cedric_talk",
        "question": "WHAAAAAT????",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "ARE YOU OKAAAAAY???"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "cedric_talk",
        "question": "DON'T WORRYYY I'M FINEEEE",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "...don't scare me like that..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "red_gatekeeper",
        "question": "[P l`ea#se do n ot ap`/p `r oac%%h.]",
        "response_character": "niko3",
        "response": "..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "plight_wtf",
        "question": "Now, of all times...!",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "...Uh"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "plight_worry",
        "question": "(Ah geez, I didn't think I was gonna run into...)",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "The elevator is missing a button, right?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "plight_worry",
        "question": "...how did you know?",
        "response_character": "niko_83c",
        "response": "..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "plight_worry",
        "question": "But... I've been here for hours and can't figure out a thing!",
        "response_character": "niko2",
        "response": "....evacuees?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "plight_worry",
        "question": "The square stuff wrecked the place yesterday...",
        "response_character": "niko3",
        "response": "Oh...."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "plight3",
        "question": "The library on the surface doubles as a shelter for situations like this.",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "I see..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "plight_worry",
        "question": "The... what?",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "Looks like we'll have to find some other way to fix the button,Player..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "plight_scared",
        "question": "HOLY FUDGE",
        "response_character": "niko3",
        "response": "..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "plight_worry",
        "question": "But... this is the only elevator in the area...",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "We'll... think of something."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "plight3",
        "question": "Let me know if you need my help with anything...",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "We found some elevators!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "plight_worry2",
        "question": "I've literally never seen another one in this area!",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "It WAS in a locked room..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "plight_worry2",
        "question": "Do they... uh... work?",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "We don't know yet..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "plight_worry",
        "question": "What...",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "You should be able to reach the lever, cuz...You're taller than me!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "plight",
        "question": "So... show me the way, I suppose...",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Mhm!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "plight_unknown",
        "question": "Work already!!!",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Huh?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "plight_unknown",
        "question": "AAAAUHGGHHHH!!!!",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "I think we should go talk to the guy first,Player..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "watcher",
        "question": "Here we are, at the eleventh hour.",
        "response_character": "niko3",
        "response": "..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "watcher",
        "question": "Maybe.",
        "response_character": "niko2",
        "response": "..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "rue_sigh",
        "question": "I'm... just glad everyone is ok.",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Same!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "rue_smile",
        "question": "We're ready to go now, Niko.",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "This one is blue."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "proto2b",
        "question": "[...]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "This one is blue."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "cedric",
        "question": "Salutations!",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "This one is green."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "rue",
        "question": "Hello.",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "This one is red."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "rue_sad",
        "question": "They're supposed to be here already...",
        "response_character": "niko3",
        "response": "..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "rue_oh",
        "question": "...",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "Cedric was going to bring him back with the memory disk, but..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "rue_sad",
        "question": "No...",
        "response_character": "niko_upset2",
        "response": "I... I'm sorry..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "rue_sad",
        "question": "There goes our only chance...",
        "response_character": "niko_upset2",
        "response": "I... I'm sorry..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "proto1",
        "question": "[...no wonder he wanted us to all be here for this.]",
        "response_character": "niko2",
        "response": "Um... what are these things, anyway?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "proto1c",
        "question": "[They... temporarily remove us from the world.]",
        "response_character": "niko2",
        "response": "....what?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "proto2b",
        "question": "[...When our keys are combined into a central location, it will activate an encrypted part of this world, which will...]",
        "response_character": "niko_what",
        "response": "*confused cat noises*"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "rue",
        "question": "Basically... these portals all represent a physical location onPlayer's machine.",
        "response_character": "niko2",
        "response": "...oooh."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "cedric_hmm",
        "question": "I... don't know what happens next, though.",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "I see..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "rue",
        "question": "You should probably askPlayeron this...",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "Right."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "plight_worry",
        "question": "...This room gives me the creeps, man...",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Oh, same!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "plight3",
        "question": "So um... what did you need help with again?",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Can you reach the lever up there?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "plight_why",
        "question": "...I'm not THAT tall!",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "(Well it was worth a shot.)"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "plight_2b",
        "question": "...wait, I got this.",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Nice!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "plight3",
        "question": "So... you coming?",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Mhm!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "rue",
        "question": "I liked to look at the far-off buildings and imagine...what kind of lives that might be behind each of the windows.",
        "response_character": "niko_upset",
        "response": "..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "rue",
        "question": "Knowing that all of this is... well...",
        "response_character": "niko_upset2",
        "response": "...fake?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "rue_sigh",
        "question": "Simulated.",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "rue_talk",
        "question": "Did he?",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "I'm... really sorry about that...  I can't imagine...how you must feel..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "rue",
        "question": "You are prevented from going home by the same...individual... who never wanted to bring you here.",
        "response_character": "niko3",
        "response": "...Huh? Who would that be?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "rue_talk",
        "question": "You... might know it as the Entity.",
        "response_character": "niko2",
        "response": "Oh..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "rue_talk",
        "question": "It was never meant to develop a mind of its own.",
        "response_character": "niko4",
        "response": "..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "rue_sigh",
        "question": "It has to bring a real person into a dying world that isn't even real.",
        "response_character": "niko3",
        "response": "..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "rue",
        "question": "...but the World Machine doesn't know that.",
        "response_character": "niko3",
        "response": "...really?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "rue_sigh",
        "question": "You can see physical manifestations of that everywhere, now...",
        "response_character": "niko4",
        "response": "The squares..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "rue_talk",
        "question": "...My creator says it's largely an involuntary process, induced by stress and the desire to self- terminate.",
        "response_character": "niko3",
        "response": "Your creator knows?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "rue_sad",
        "question": "...by the time he realized the actual root of the problem, our home world's remaining lifespan was measured in mere days.",
        "response_character": "niko4",
        "response": "...Oh."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "rue_sad",
        "question": "The odds are against us... we have no chance of taming it.",
        "response_character": "niko2",
        "response": "Taming?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "rue",
        "question": "Do you... know what a robot is?",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Yeah?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "rue",
        "question": "No, I mean.Do you KNOW what a robot is?",
        "response_character": "niko2",
        "response": "...um."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "rue",
        "question": "A robot is not a real person, is it?",
        "response_character": "niko2",
        "response": "...right."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "rue",
        "question": "...but this was more of a limitation than anything else.",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "Ah, that makes sense."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "rue",
        "question": "In a way, that's what happened to The World Machine.",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "The... code conflicts thing?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "rue_smile",
        "question": "In a way, it's starting to believe itself as a \"real\", valid individual.",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "rue_sad",
        "question": "It doesn't want to take you along with it.",
        "response_character": "niko3",
        "response": "..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "ling",
        "question": "Can I... get you anything to eat?",
        "response_character": "niko2",
        "response": "No thank you!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "ling_sigh",
        "question": "Terrible, isn't it?",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "Yeah..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "mason",
        "question": "This stinks!",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "Sorry to hear..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "mason",
        "question": "Is that true?",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "...yeah..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "mason",
        "question": "...say, how is she doing?",
        "response_character": "niko_distressed2",
        "response": "..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "mason",
        "question": "...she's... gone, isn't she?",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "She said she was using up the last of her powers..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "mason",
        "question": "She always did her best to protect everyone...",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "I can't sleep now,Player."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "plight_sigh",
        "question": "You got more important stuff to deal with...",
        "response_character": "niko2",
        "response": "...let's see if this elevator works."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "plight_2",
        "question": "I'll uh...go get the evacuees, I suppose...",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Mhm!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "plight_scared",
        "question": "WHAT IS GOING ON.",
        "response_character": "niko_shock",
        "response": "Nooo!!!!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "plight_worry",
        "question": "I can hear them just outside the door...",
        "response_character": "niko3",
        "response": "Yeah..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "plight_worry2",
        "question": "Go do... what you need to do....",
        "response_character": "niko3",
        "response": "But... what about you?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "plight_worry",
        "question": "I'll... figure something out...",
        "response_character": "niko4",
        "response": "Okay..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "cedric_upset",
        "question": "Let go of me!!!",
        "response_character": "niko2",
        "response": "...Cedric?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "kip_sigh",
        "question": "*Sigh*",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "...Miss?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "kip_pout",
        "question": "Come on, we have to get out of here.",
        "response_character": "niko2",
        "response": "Where... to?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "kip_sigh",
        "question": "Where everyone else is right now.",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Uh... cheese?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george1_hm",
        "question": "George rates it 10 out of 10.",
        "response_character": "niko2",
        "response": "Ooh..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george2_sigh",
        "question": "Took me forever to edit...",
        "response_character": "niko2",
        "response": "Ooh..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george3_sigh",
        "question": "...you know... the first robot you met in our world...",
        "response_character": "niko2",
        "response": "Yeah."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george3_sigh",
        "question": "It... would've been useful to your friend, I think...",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "...yeah."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george4_golly",
        "question": "Remember Prophetbot? The first robot you met in our world?",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "Yeah..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george4_smile",
        "question": "The Author's book was so detailed... really made me appreciate how much work went into him!",
        "response_character": "niko2",
        "response": "Ooh..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george5_smile",
        "question": "I really enjoyed editing it!",
        "response_character": "niko2",
        "response": "Ooh..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george6_point",
        "question": "You remember Prophetbot?The first robot you met in our world?",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "...yeah?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george6_point",
        "question": "...was the freshest book I've ever edited, man!",
        "response_character": "niko2",
        "response": "Ooh..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "kip_pout",
        "question": "Please be careful out there...",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Mhm!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "bookbot",
        "question": "[IF YOU HAVE AN INQUIRY. PLEASE APPROACH FROM THE FRONT.]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "I'm good, thanks!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "bookbot",
        "question": "[WE APOLOGIZE FOR THE INCONVENIENCE.]",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "It's okay..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george5_smile",
        "question": "Hello, little one!",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Hi..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george6_point",
        "question": "How's it goin', lil fella?",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "Bad."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "kip_pout",
        "question": "I don't know why he was being so insistent!",
        "response_character": "niko4",
        "response": "He... he said he needed to go rebuild a robot..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "kip_pout",
        "question": "Oh, you know him?",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "Yeah."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george1",
        "question": "So THAT's what he needed that book for!",
        "response_character": "niko2",
        "response": "...come again?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george1",
        "question": "A boy with white hair and goggles ran in here not long ago.",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "That's Cedric, yeah..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george2",
        "question": "Y'all talking about a kid with white hair and goggles?",
        "response_character": "niko2",
        "response": "That's Cedric, yeah..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george2_no",
        "question": "THE NERVE OF THAT KID!",
        "response_character": "niko4",
        "response": "Um..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george3",
        "question": "Are you talking about... a boy with white hair and googles?",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "That's Cedric, yeah..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george4_golly",
        "question": "...no wonder why he needed that book!",
        "response_character": "niko2",
        "response": "...come again?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george4_golly",
        "question": "Hat... white hair... goggles...",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "That's Cedric, yeah..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george5",
        "question": "Could that be... why he needed that book?",
        "response_character": "niko2",
        "response": "...come again?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george5",
        "question": "Ah... a young man with white hair and green glasses ran in earlier.",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "That's Cedric, yeah..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george6",
        "question": "Y'all talkin' about a lil' dude with white hair and goggles, right?",
        "response_character": "niko4",
        "response": "That's Cedric, yeah..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "kip_worry",
        "question": "That was...",
        "response_character": "niko3",
        "response": "...the labs?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "kip_worry",
        "question": "That poor kid!!!",
        "response_character": "niko_shock",
        "response": "No!!!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "kip_sigh",
        "question": "I'm sorry about your friend...",
        "response_character": "niko_distressed2",
        "response": "..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george1_hm",
        "question": "The messiah will not walk into danger on my watch!",
        "response_character": "niko3",
        "response": "But..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george2_grr",
        "question": "Kid, there is NO way we're letting you out there.",
        "response_character": "niko3",
        "response": "But I really have to..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george3_cry",
        "question": "You... shouldn't go out there....!",
        "response_character": "niko_distressed",
        "response": "But..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george5_hmm",
        "question": "Sweetie, you know we can't let you just walk into danger!",
        "response_character": "niko3",
        "response": "But..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george6_shrug",
        "question": "Fire... squares...",
        "response_character": "niko4",
        "response": "But..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "kip_sigh",
        "question": "...however long that takes.",
        "response_character": "niko2",
        "response": "But....but..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "kip_sigh",
        "question": "But now I... I'm starting to understand...",
        "response_character": "niko4",
        "response": "..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "kip_pout",
        "question": "...blissfully ignoring the fact that you are just a lost child.",
        "response_character": "niko3",
        "response": "Well..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "kip_sigh",
        "question": "We must seem so ungrateful...",
        "response_character": "niko3",
        "response": "..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "kip_pout",
        "question": "...",
        "response_character": "niko3",
        "response": "I..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "kip_pout",
        "question": "...",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "...Player... do you remember?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "kip_pout",
        "question": "You... what...",
        "response_character": "niko3",
        "response": "I..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george4_omg",
        "question": "I KNOW RIGHT!!! IT HAPPENED RIGHT IN FRONT OF OUR EYES!!!",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "george6_smile",
        "question": "You're real strong, you know that?",
        "response_character": "niko4",
        "response": "I..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "kip_pout",
        "question": "But... promise us you'll be careful, okay?",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Mhm!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "rue",
        "question": "You're here!!!",
        "response_character": "niko2",
        "response": "Rue!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "rue_talk",
        "question": "Niko!",
        "response_character": "niko2",
        "response": "Are you... are you Rue?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "rue",
        "question": "Did you... already meet the others?",
        "response_character": "niko2",
        "response": "Yeah... but..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "rue",
        "question": "Come on, let's go back to the clock room.",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "A bulletin board with lots of papers on it."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "cedric_sigh",
        "question": "Too bad there's no water in here...",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Black clovers in a glass case."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "proto2b",
        "question": "[Well, the door does not exist without us there.]",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "Guess I can't go back out, huh..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "proto2",
        "question": "[...Do you need to?]",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "...not really."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "rue_oh",
        "question": "...The World Machine.",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "It's a blueprint!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "proto2b",
        "question": "[...That's called a blueprint, Niko.]",
        "response_character": "niko_pancakes",
        "response": "...So THAT's what a blueprint is!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "proto_eyeclosed",
        "question": "[I am... grateful, to see it again.]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "It's a stack of books."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "en_distressed",
        "question": "[Niko...]",
        "response_character": "niko_surprised",
        "response": "AAAH!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "en_upset",
        "question": "[It's not like my physical form is good for that.]",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "Ah..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "en_eyeclosed",
        "question": "[Get out of here.][Let me meet my end in peace.]",
        "response_character": "niko4",
        "response": "..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "en_upset_meow",
        "question": "[...I'm sorry, I-]",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "It's alright..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "en_upset2",
        "question": "[No living being should be in this place, Niko...]",
        "response_character": "niko2",
        "response": "Is this... the Tower?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "en_eyeclosed",
        "question": "[...Inside my head, so to speak...]",
        "response_character": "niko4",
        "response": "..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "en4",
        "question": "[How?]",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "Rue, Cedric, Prototype...They all... told me bits and pieces."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "en4",
        "question": "[When?]",
        "response_character": "niko2",
        "response": "Wait... You don't know about that?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "en_upset_meow",
        "question": "[The story... wasn't written into my protocol at all.]",
        "response_character": "niko2",
        "response": "Oh, right... Rue told me something about how your creator had to alter the code."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "en_upset",
        "question": "[I couldn't see anything there!]",
        "response_character": "niko2",
        "response": "..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "en_distressed2",
        "question": "[I panicked.]",
        "response_character": "niko2",
        "response": "That was when... the cave in happened...."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "en_upset",
        "question": "[...]",
        "response_character": "niko4",
        "response": "..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "en_distressed_meow",
        "question": "[I really am a flawed machine, aren't I?]",
        "response_character": "niko3",
        "response": "..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "en_distressed_talk",
        "question": "[What kind of machine would...]",
        "response_character": "niko3",
        "response": "..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "en",
        "question": "[I'm...]",
        "response_character": "niko2",
        "response": "..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "en_eyeclosed",
        "question": "[...Forcing him to exit and restart testing again and again.]",
        "response_character": "niko2",
        "response": "...Why... would you do that?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "en_upset2",
        "question": "[Some of them got too close, and...]",
        "response_character": "niko3",
        "response": "..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "en_distressed",
        "question": "[Their code... my code... couldn't handle it.]",
        "response_character": "niko3",
        "response": "..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "en_eyeclosed",
        "question": "[Previous iterations of the world had more people, you know...]",
        "response_character": "niko3",
        "response": "..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "en_distressed_meow",
        "question": "[...I was so scared, Niko!!!]",
        "response_character": "niko2",
        "response": "..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "en_eyeclosed",
        "question": "[...But I don't think I can make it happen.]",
        "response_character": "niko2",
        "response": "But... I know I can't go back home without saving the world for real."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "en_upset2",
        "question": "[...]",
        "response_character": "niko5",
        "response": "I... know the original ending your creator put in was a happy one."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "en_distressed2",
        "question": "[That part of my code has been long corrupted.]",
        "response_character": "niko2",
        "response": "That's ok. I would still like to know."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "en5",
        "question": "[And then, credits would scroll.]",
        "response_character": "niko2",
        "response": "...credits?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "en2",
        "question": "[THAT's where you would have been able to leave.]",
        "response_character": "niko3",
        "response": "...and why is it that you can't do it now?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "en_less_sad",
        "question": "[Oh... I don't know...]",
        "response_character": "niko3",
        "response": "...it sounds like you're always fighting yourself."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "en_distressed2",
        "question": "[...][...You can tell, huh...]",
        "response_character": "niko3",
        "response": "It's the whole thing about conflicts in your code, isn't it?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "en2",
        "question": "[Machines are built with a fundamental law, which is...]",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed2",
        "response": "\"Never let a living being come to harm\"."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "en_distressed2",
        "question": "[This fake world... isn't worth that risk.]",
        "response_character": "niko4",
        "response": "But..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "en_distressed_talk",
        "question": "[It's pointless to put you in danger to save them... to save me.]",
        "response_character": "niko3",
        "response": "I... don't think that's.... true."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "en4",
        "question": "[Yeah?]",
        "response_character": "niko2",
        "response": "So... if this session wasn't supposed to happen."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "en3",
        "question": "[I...]",
        "response_character": "niko_distressed2",
        "response": "You said it yourself... when you didn't know what was happening, you kinda just... stopped working for a while."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "en4",
        "question": "[...]",
        "response_character": "niko_distressed2",
        "response": "Even if it meant... messing up their own code..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "en_distressed2",
        "question": "[.....]",
        "response_character": "niko_distressed",
        "response": "You might not think they are real, but..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "en_upset",
        "question": "[.......]",
        "response_character": "niko_distressed2",
        "response": "And... if they're all supposed to be extensions of your code..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "en_upset",
        "question": "[...]",
        "response_character": "niko3",
        "response": "Can you... try to put me through the ending?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "en_distressed2",
        "question": "[I'll just... put you in danger...]",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "I...'ll risk it."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "en_distressed",
        "question": "[I'm not tamed!]",
        "response_character": "niko_upset_meow",
        "response": "...yes you are!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "en_upset2",
        "question": "[...]",
        "response_character": "niko3",
        "response": "Taming is when a real person cares about you, right?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "en3",
        "question": "[...]",
        "response_character": "niko_cry",
        "response": "Why... do you thinkPlayerwould keep coming back?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "en",
        "question": "[...I...]",
        "response_character": "niko_cry",
        "response": "Why do you thinkPlayerwould restart even after the ending?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "en3",
        "question": "[...]",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "...I thinkPlayerwants to save the both of us."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "en_upset_meow",
        "question": "[I'm scared...]",
        "response_character": "niko3",
        "response": "You can do it, I know you can!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "en_distressed2",
        "question": "[What if you get hurt?]",
        "response_character": "niko2",
        "response": "It's fine... It's fine..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver",
        "question": "[Off you go, now...]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "So, um... You..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver_eyeclosed",
        "question": "[I don't believe I've ever actually properly introduced myself.Sorry for that.]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "It's fine!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver",
        "question": "[Nice to meet you, too.]",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "So... do you like being a robot?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "proto2",
        "question": "[Why this, all of a sudden?]",
        "response_character": "niko2",
        "response": "Well, I'm gonna leave soon, so I just wanted to ask one more question!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "rue_smile",
        "question": "I mean...do you like being a person?",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Of course!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "maize_smile2",
        "question": "Hello, messiah...",
        "response_character": "niko_shock",
        "response": "...Plant lady? But I thought you..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "cedric_smile",
        "question": "We are forever in your debt.",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "I'm glad we could help!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "rue_smile",
        "question": "You managed to tame the World Machine, Niko!",
        "response_character": "niko2",
        "response": "I... feel like the World Machine has been tamed this whole time."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "proto2b",
        "question": "[...or not.]",
        "response_character": "niko_eyeclosed",
        "response": "Well, just throwing that idea out there!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "plight_sigh",
        "question": "Glad to see you in one piece...",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Glad to see you're ok, too!After the whole elevator thing."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "plight_wtf",
        "question": "...AM I DEAD!?",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "No no, you're fine!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "plight_worry",
        "question": "I can't work when I'm dead!",
        "response_character": "niko2",
        "response": "..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "rue",
        "question": "You... already know what to expect, right?",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Mhm..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver2",
        "question": "...Messiah?",
        "response_character": "niko_surprised",
        "response": "ROBOT LADY!!!!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver2",
        "question": "[But then, I....ended up here unscathed.]",
        "response_character": "niko3",
        "response": "Is that so..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver2",
        "question": "[We can't be... in the Tower, can we?]",
        "response_character": "niko6",
        "response": "I'm actually not sure myself..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver2",
        "question": "[...where did YOU come from, anyway?]",
        "response_character": "niko2",
        "response": "The room where the World Machine was..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver2",
        "question": "[...pardon?]",
        "response_character": "niko5",
        "response": "I... think the World Machine is trying to remember, now..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver2",
        "question": "[World... Machine, huh...]",
        "response_character": "niko2",
        "response": "Oh... I'm not sure if I should tell you this, but..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver",
        "question": "[It... looks like a few more people are showing up.]",
        "response_character": "niko_pancakes",
        "response": "Oh!!!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver2",
        "question": "[Are they... people you know?]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "It's... a bit too far to tell."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "rowbot",
        "question": "[THE HEAD ENGINEER CAN HELP ME DO NOT WORRY.]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Alright..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "rowbot",
        "question": "[HELLO.]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Hi!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "rowbot",
        "question": "[I... CANNOT MOVE.]",
        "response_character": "niko2",
        "response": "Oh, yeah..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "calamus_smile",
        "question": "We're glad we met you, Niko!",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Same!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "alula_gasp",
        "question": "You're okay too!",
        "response_character": "niko2",
        "response": "Did you guys just get here?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "calamus_heh",
        "question": "Biggest scare of my life, for sure...",
        "response_character": "niko2",
        "response": "Ooh..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "calamus_shame",
        "question": "...wait, are we?",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "No no, you're fine!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "alula_gasp",
        "question": "That's even better than limbo!",
        "response_character": "niko_what",
        "response": "Good... question."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "calamus_sad",
        "question": "Phew.",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "They also said you'll be able to go back to your home very soon!"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "en_eyeclosed",
        "question": "[It's not like I'm going anywhere.]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Some sort of small machine."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver",
        "question": "[Let's go.]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "It's not safe to use this minecart anymore,Player."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "silver",
        "question": "[Let's go.]",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "I can see a green glow in the distance."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "green_gatekeeper",
        "question": "[Please do not approach.This area is dangerous.]",
        "response_character": "niko2",
        "response": "..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "plight_unknown",
        "question": "Work already!!!",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "Huh?"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "plight_unknown",
        "question": "WHY. ISN'T. THIS. WORKING??!?",
        "response_character": "niko_speak",
        "response": "I think we should go talk to the guy first,Player..."
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "kip",
        "question": "Sigh",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Hey"
    },
    {
        "question_maker": "kip",
        "question": "come on, we have to get outta here.",
        "response_character": "niko",
        "response": "Where?"
    }
]